Heat. Heat. N.
Heat.
Hey, Heat.
[Music]
Hello everybody. Good evening, good day
everyone wherever you are in the world
and welcome back to the Ask Abijit show.
So today we are going to discuss
geopolitics and we're going to take
questions from the super chat and the
live chat. Before we do that let's see
who is there on the live chat with us.
Who else who all do we have? Event
countdown imatistic ICMBBS Aush Singh
Ashtavakra Mr. Jam Amit Pande Patriotic
Rakit Mishra Samatish Sakam Jashrotia
Mish Mr. Jam Abuai Singh Hitanu Ma from
Gujarat. Hello mystic skrity
mahadev shivasai namaskarum ultimate
power namaste anonymous scientist event
countdown
uh ugram iatistic ashtavakra bhaskar
kayatwal ashwani
abhishek shukla kumlyak space injured
soccer player well I get I hope you get
well soon netizen
um uh pratush sujit shanaganda fishbal
All naman Aurora feeds strong man.
Tanesh Pande Makloin Ram Manchits Sutara
Ananta Subramanyam ad meet from Gujarat.
Sorab Alsh. Who else do we have? Anand
subman once again. Anish Panchchal,
Aayush, Gupta, Saksham, Sarab, Omar,
Shindai, Sakena,
Jay, Guman,
Vinay, Ray, Bhihar, Ananta, Subramanyam,
Anime, Pratish, Tatip, Satellite,
Daksha, Ankita, Mango, Ananta, Samyak,
and everybody else. Everyone else Priyan
Kumar Pratish Tatip Namaste Juts Natumar
Namaste Daksha Ram Ram Omar Boxer
Sasmmit
Vinay
uh godliness Manisha Priyanka Jabalia
Sorab Mr. Saka feel strong man and karan
narawat prashant panar
hershwaran kaspa
ami amisha mishra hello lraj aditi
marcos ashwani
okay random shots pranam pranam okay so
we're going to take questions from the
super chat before we do that I have a
recommendation for you all and yeah I'm
not recommending uh uh my books I'm not
doing that right now I'm recommending
something else. Considering what's
happening in the world right now, I will
highly recommend that you all watch a
couple of my old live streams, Ask
Abijit episodes. Which ones? Here. Ask
Abijit 38, Taliban Conquers Afghanistan
from 2021
and Ask Abijit 40, Afghanistan situation
once again from 2021. Both these
episodes went live in the year 2021.
when the Taliban actually conquered
Afghanistan.
And why am I recommending that you watch
these old episodes?
Why am I recommending that? It's because
they are super relevant. If you want to
understand what's happening right now,
watch those episodes.
I you could say I have made some
forecasts in those episodes. At that
time when the Taliban took Afghanistan
there was this great atmosphere of gloom
and doom in India. India's great
geopolitical experts, strategic affairs
experts were saying that oh Pakistan has
won, Pakistan has won, Rahul Pindia has
won, Afghanistan has gone to Pakistan,
we are doomed. That's what everyone was
saying. And I was saying you are all
mistaken. Please understand what's
really happening. So I will highly
recommend that you watch these two
episodes 38 Taliban conquers Afghanistan
and Askabit 40 which is about the
Afghanistan situation at the time.
Okay, with that said, all right, let's
do today's live stream. Let's take the
questions. Let's begin. Anonymous
anonymous scientist says Amir Khan
Mutaki's visit is quite significant
comments. Well, it is very significant
of course. Um, so he's the Taliban
foreign minister, the foreign minister
of Afghanistan. First of all, our
government, our ministry of external
affairs has referred to him multiple
times now during this visit as
Afghanistan's foreign minister. Not the
acting foreign minister, not something
like that. The actual foreign minister
and our external affairs minister Dr.
Jashankar had a proper meeting with him.
So it's foreign minister to foreign
minister. So we are essentially giving
de facto recognition to to the Taliban
as the legitimate government of
Afghanistan.
Right. And Mr. Amir Khan Mutaki was
treated super well during this visit. He
uh visited his Alma Matar which is
Deoband
Dul Ulum that institution uh which is
the the fountain place of the Taliban.
That's where the Taliban has emerged
from the Taliban are theis.
So he went there. He was given a grand
welcome there. Then he comes back to
Delhi and uh participates in various
events and does press conferences.
Overall it was an extremely warm welcome
given to Mr. Amir Khan Muttaki and I
don't think he has ever been he has ever
been treated this well anywhere even in
his own country. So uh very significant
and why is this? It's because we have
common enemy. We have a common enemy
which is Pakistan.
>> And the day Mr. Muttahi came to India,
the the Pakistanis launched an air
strike on Kabul and then last night the
Taliban responded properly by launching
attacks on various Pakistani posts along
the the Durand line which is the
so-called border between the two
countries between the artificial
temporary nation and Gandhar and
apparently there have been lots of
Pakistani casualties and so on. Uh so
the Pakistanis wanted to give this
message to the Afghans that you know
India can't help you. So the Taliban is
giving the message to Pakistan that we
don't need help. We are not doing this
for India's help. We can deal with you
ourselves. So yeah, so essentially the
Taliban is pivoting towards India.
Afghanistan is pivoting towards India
and essentially towards Russia and China
also. That's what's happening. And
Pakistan as we know has become a US
vasal. So we are seeing this
reconfiguration of the world order. And
this all comes in the background of
Bagram. The Americans want Bagram. Trump
says I want Bagram. Who the hell are you
to say that you want Bagram? It's not uh
it's it's Afghan property, isn't it? You
can't just go and grab air bases and
military bases wherever you want. So the
Taliban says no, we will not give you
Bram and that's the context in which all
of this is happening. So we are seeing a
reconfiguration of the world order. We
are seeing Afghanistan pivot towards
India and uh overall it's it's good that
this is happening. So pretty
significant. Team talks Dharma says what
are your thoughts on the PC prize? What
is a PC prize? Peace prize. Nobel Peace
Prize. Is that what you're talking
about? Also, does this decision mean
that the committee is not controlled by
the state? Trump. Okay. In case you're
referring to the Nobel Peace Prize, what
are my thoughts? It's a joke. The Nobel
Peace Prize is pure politics now. Pure
politics.
Like they once gave the Nobel Peace
Prize to Muhammad Yunus, right? The
Bangladeshi individual puppet leader or
whatever the hell he is right now,
adviser.
Uh so they gave that Nobel prize to the
guy many years before he he was put in
that position. So it was all pre-planned
right. Uh so similarly this this lady I
don't know who she is what she's
achieved in her life what she has done
what she represents she seems to be very
strongly aligned with the United States
and their regime change aspirations in
Venezuela. Right? So she essentially is
a stoogge of a foreign power working
against the interests of her country
and she says that she's working for
democracy. So democracy is in the
interest of everybody. And then the
Nobel Nobel Prize uh Twitter account
puts out a poll on Twitter that do you
agree that democracy is is the the
precondition for lasting peace in the
world. What utter nonsense. Democracy is
not a precondition for lasting peace
anywhere in the world. So overall this
is a joke. The Nobel Prize, Nobel Peace
Prize has become politicized. It has
been sourced for for a very long time. I
mean, Henry Kissinger was given the
Nobel Peace Prize. Come on. Barack Obama
was given the Nobel Peace Prize. And a
lot of nobodyies are given the Nobel
Peace Prize and elevated to a to a
position of of prominence. Malala Yusf
Zai. Why was she given the prize?
Because she got shot.
And who else? Who is this Kash Satyari
guy? And and God knows who else. Teresa
Teresa apparently got the prize. So it's
it's it's it's now become like like a
100 times more prominent version of the
Maxis prize. The Maxis surprise is given
to people who assist foreign powers in
regime change operations in their own
countries. Typically not all not all not
all let's just put that on the record.
Not all but many of these individuals
who receive Nobel Max prizes are agents
of foreign countries in their own
countries. Many not all. So the Nobel
Prize has become that that sort of
thing. The Nobel Peace Prize at least
and the physics prize is is also a joke.
Now there there seems to be a policy in
the physics prize that you will not not
give a physics pri Nobel Nobel Physics
prize to anyone who is less than 95
years old or something maybe less than
75 years old. Don't give to anyone who's
young and who will be motivated by the
prize. Give it to someone who's done,
finished and done and dusted with their
life. So the Nobel has become a joke
now. That's all I would say.
ICMBBS says, "What's your take on
Takachi?" I have no idea on Takachi.
I've not paid attention. It doesn't
matter who Takachi is. Okay, let's read.
She seems like an ultra nationalist and
not what the Yanks would want if
elected. Could she think could she
change things geopolitically?
We'll see if it happens. Look, the
Japanese prime minister doesn't matter.
There's only been one prime minister
since 1945 who actually mattered and he
was taken care of. His name was Shinszu
AB, right? Sadly, apart from Shinszu AB,
no other Japanese prime minister has
mattered in any way whatsoever
geopolitically or any in any other way.
The Japanese prime ministership is a
revolving door thing. Someone comes and
someone goes, someone comes and comes,
someone goes. No, Buru Takkeshta and God
knows who else you had. I don't even
remember the names anymore. Nakason
Nakason was there a long time ago.
Akishta and uh I don't even remember who
the last two three guys were. They came
and went. Came and went. So Taki if she
comes well I don't know. We'll see if
she becomes she does anything of any
significance. Beyond that I I don't
really pay attention to who becomes the
Japanese prime minister. It doesn't
matter. See Japan is a country under
foreign occupation. This prime
ministership, this parliament, the laws
etc. are just for show.
The person who is prime minister doesn't
get to control anything whatsoever.
They just go I mean they take care of
some internal affairs and they're like a
mayor essentially. No actual real power.
The actual real power lies with the US
generals who run the country.
So doesn't really matter unfortunately
sadly. And that's it's actually tragic
for Japan. Tragic. DMI says one was
Trump's speech push just a cover to back
pro US machador who could give America
vital oil access against Russia China
and could India's next next major
operation launched from Afghan soil I
think it's a little too early to jump to
conclusions about India launching
project Synindur operation Zindur from
Afghan soil it's a little early for that
I don't expect that to happen unless the
Pakistanis cross certain lines
um so I answer the question first
because it's two questions in one. Um
I think it may be beneficial, it may be
worth exploring if for India to uh maybe
supply a few missiles to Afghanistan,
certain specific kinds of missiles.
Maybe not the Brahmos for example, but
maybe the Akash missile system. The
Akash is something that the Pakistanis
are by now frightened of. Okay. It will
take out any Pakistani aircraft. The any
kind of aircraft the Pakistanis have
that tries to come over Kawul the Akash
aircraft will take it down the Akash
missile system. Maybe we should supply
some some Akash systems to to
Afghanistan. That'll set the cat among
the pigs. But I don't expect India's
next major operation to launch from
Afghan soil. Not an Indian operation.
Maybe Afghan operations could launch
from Afghan soil. So my point is
operations could possibly soon be
launched from Afghan soil depending on
Pakistan's attitude and behavior but
those will be Afghan operations and
maybe there will be moral support from
India perhaps because Pakistan is a
terrorist nation. Imagine the Taliban
considers Pakistan to be a terrorist
nation. The Taliban were tarnished as
terrorists for decades, right? And they
are complaining that Pakistan is terror
is a terrorist nation. They harbor
terrorists. What on earth is Donald
Trump doing? He is aligning himself with
a nation that has the worst reputation
of terrorism in the world. Of course, he
he went and met a headdropper, didn't
he? Uh Al Gulani, the terrorist who had
a $10 million bounty on his head, a
terrorist who was a professional
headdropper. And now Trump goes and
meets him. So, so these people uh
morality and ethics don't matter.
National interest matters. That's
actually the way the way the world
works. That's what Achari Chanaka taught
us. First question, was Trump's peace
prize push just a cover to back pro- US
much? Could be. Could be. Could be.
Could be. Yeah, it's possible.
Godliness says people belonging to the
world's oldest Saraspati Hindu
civilization. The story of the Pashupati
seal. The devotees of Rajar Ram the Lord
Dharma sadly today shake the hands of
evil Islamic Islamist Taliban.
Yeah.
Who is the Taliban fighting? Pakistan.
Would you like us to shake hands with
Pakistan or Taliban? I am perfectly fine
with shaking hands with the Taliban. The
Taliban are not anti-India in any way
whatsoever. I I I said at the beginning
of this live stream, watch those two
episodes, Ask Abij 30 and ask 40.
At that time I had made it clear that
Taliban is not anti-India and it's not
pro Pakistan. It's not a Pakistani
puppet.
I am perfectly happy to shake hands with
the Taliban. Um as long as they don't
have any any anti-India uh you know
agenda and they don't. They want to be
left alone to rule their country in
whichever way they feel fit and I think
uh they have the right to do that.
They have brought back law and order in
their country. They have destroyed
corruption to a large extent. The roads
in Kabul are better allegedly
than allegedly many the roads in most
major cities allegedly in India. The
Taliban are doing a lot of good for the
country. It's an Islamic country. So
they run the country according to
Islamic laws. It's now an Islamic
country. It is what it is. Thousand
years ago it was ours. It was our the
Taliban are descendants of our people.
Anyway, that's a that's forget about
that. So if you have a problem with them
you know giving women secondass status
well it's their religion that does that
and we should not comment about
someone's religion right and if we shake
hands with them I see nothing wrong with
that none whatsoever
the world is like I said doesn't work on
the basis of ethics and morality and u
you know all that stuff I mean we don't
we shake hands with beef eaters by the
way
h if you're talking about devotees of
Raja Ram and all that. Aren't we shaking
hands with beef eaters and hugging
beefeeders?
So then why not shake hands with the
Taliban?
I don't get it.
Amisha says, "Why is the border tension
rising between Pakistan and Afghanistan?
Saudi Pakistan really didn't even last a
month. What does the Pak Taliban foreign
minister visit mean to India?" Like I
said, it it means that uh Afghanistan is
pivoting towards India. India and
Afghanistan have shared interests lot of
shared interests
and we have a very annoying shared enemy
right we are not Pakistan's enemy
Pakistan is our is our enemy and
Pakistan is willing to to sell itself
piece by piece to the Americans so that
they can America can encircle India so
that's what uh the Pakistanis represent
and they are a nuisance in the
neighborhood none of their three
neighbors likes Their
three neighbors are India, Afghanistan
and Iran. And all three of the neighbors
wish that there was somebody else over
there.
Ideally the situation should have been
that India and Persia have a shared
border and the third border is
Afghanistan. There should be no
Pakistan. Then there'll be no terrorism.
Everybody can live in peace like we used
to in the past.
>> So uh so India and uh Afghanistan have
this shared problem. Pakistan how do we
deal with this? So we'll find ways to
deal with the Pakistanis, right? And we
have other interests in Afghanistan. We
have been u we have invested more than
$33 billion worth of you know resources,
money in Afghanistan. We've built dams.
We've built we are we have we have run
agricultural projects. We have built the
Salma dam like like I said we have
invested a lot in Afghanistan and it's a
long-term investment. It's not something
for short-term returns. So we're going
to we're going to continue that. uh and
it is important for India that
Afghanistan remains stable. We don't
want another nonsense war over there
which last 20 30 years. We don't need
that. We want stability in our
neighborhood. The only source of
instability now is Pakistan and it's a
shared concern for India and
Afghanistan. So I'm sure that we will we
would have discussed the Pakistan issue
mainly and also Afghanistan's
development. We don't want any
humanitarian crisis in Afghanistan. We
want to ensure that whatever supplies
we're sending there reach reach there.
the Afghans want us to you know uh
invest in their mining sector and all
I'm sure that that is very feasible so
all of that right and when it comes to
the Saudi Pakistan treaty look it's
nothing to the Saudi Pakistan treaty is
entirely aimed at India and this treaty
is actually orchestrated by the United
States the objective is to is is to aim
at India not at Taliban so the Taliban
Pakistan battle which happened may may
still be happening perhaps I don't know
this that is something that was not
anticipated and the Saudis will not want
to get involved in no in any way
whatsoever in a Pakistan Afghanistan
fight they don't want to be get involved
in that they actually don't even want to
be involved in a Pakistan India fight
but the Americans have arm twisted them
into this thing
so yeah the Pakistanis now claimed that
the that Afghanistan has attacked
Pakistan and so on the Saudis have
stayed out of it we are see we are
watching the issue with great concern
blah blah blah. It may be a different
see the the objective of this Pakistan
Saudi Arabia defense treaty etc is to
launder arms ammunition and weapon
systems the Americans don't want to sell
everything directly to Pakistan they
will launder it through Saudi Arabia and
the objective is to make Pakistan strong
enough so that it can withstand the next
operations in so
uh Marcos says how do you see India
Taliban meeting explain explain explain
I see it as a very positive Like I
explained very positive thing.
Excellent.
Ritwick says what USA China received
from Myanmar rare earth minerals. What
India receives from Myanmar? Cookie
terrorists. Yes. They are not
immigrants. They're illegal infiltrators
and they're terrorists. Why can't India
increase its influence over Myanmar when
it's right in our backyard?
I'm not sure what we are doing visav
Myanmar. I'm not sure what we're doing.
It looks like the government of India
has been uh appeasing the cookie
terrorists for a very long time.
The cookie terrorists are not Indian.
Not Indian by blood, not Indian by
ethnicity, not Indian by culture, by
civilization, by religion, anything. No
matter how much you appease a snake, the
snake will always want to bite you when
the opportunity arises.
Right? So does it not make sense to to
set set things right for the native
inhabitants of of Manipur in the entire
region overall the Nagas and the mateies
the mateies and the Nagas h why why why
is a certain ethnic group confined to
like 3% of the states state's area it's
a path hide
so I'm not sure what the government of
India is doing maybe there are some
constraints that we are not aware of
that's also a possibility but I'm not
sure why can't India increase its
influence over Myanmar we can we should
this track 2.5 diplomacy and that
nonsense is is waste of time let's have
a proper thing with Myanmar I would say
all this slow steady little things a
bunch of suits ancient suits visiting
some parts of Myanmar and doing having
some some conversations and some
speeches and stuff that's a waste of
time what we need is is is to deal with
the root cause of the terrorism which is
which is actually on Myanmar soil on
teranmar territory. Um the rare earth
minerals the problem is that you know
the rare earth minerals are located
right on the Myanmar China border
in the north east of Myanmar.
It's like a stone throw away from the
Chinese border. So the Chinese receive
these things and I'm sure they pay the
Myanmar's well for that. not the Myanmar
government but whoever is in is ruling
that part of Myanmar because see the
Myanmar government has lost control over
significant portions of its territory.
Um so I have been a proponent of India
increasing its influence in Myanmar for
a very long time for decades
but uh
I'm sure we should do that but I I don't
know maybe there's something up maybe
the government of India has some plans
or maybe not I have no idea.
Um Dan Dave says why has India failed to
product great products in tech failed to
product great products failed to produce
great products and technology. we are
still service based. Indian success in
US does not benefit India anyway. It's
because of the fundamental defects and
deficiencies in the system.
Uh first of all the the old Indian
entrepreneurs the old companies like you
know all the IT firms and all they were
solely focused on profits
not on developing any technology
whatsoever. They wanted to use you know
the good old labor arbitrage method to
make money. The American companies they
are willing to pay us X dollars per hour
for software development work and I will
pay my my employees a fraction of that
and the rest I will pocket. So let's say
uh I am billing the US company that I'm
working that my employees are working
for. Let's say I'm billing the American
company $100 an hour but I'll pay my
employees
a fraction of that. Maybe $20 an hour
even less. not an hourly rate maybe a
monthly rate you know monthly salary
that's it do overtime whatever you get a
monthly salary that way you can pocket
million you know huge amounts of money
and that's why all that's how all these
Indian IT firms became big
so they did not want to take any risks
you develop a product and it may or may
not work in the market who wants to take
the risk we have a tried andrue method
of labor arbitrage that is guaranteed to
give us money to to keep making money
minting money for for us. So let's keep
doing that. So that's been the mindset
and whatever profits they make, they
will not reinvest that into R&D or
anything. No, they will give it to the
shareholders or whatever. That's been
the mindset. The good old I don't know
what to call that mindset, but that's
what what it's been. Uh secondly, we
don't have so that's the problem of the
big companies the the infoscesses and
the
whatever it was whatever the other
companies are right when it comes to
new tech entrepreneurs
uh they want to make unicorns that are
valued at a billion dollars on paper but
most of those unfortunately are actually
lossmaking companies.
They want to reach a valuation of a
billion dollars and make an exit or
something. That's another problem that
we see. Thirdly, there may be lots of
people with great ideas but they don't
have access to funding, right? Venture
capital. I mean, let's say somebody in
some city in India has a great idea for
a product and they want to develop it
but but they don't have access to
funding. Where will they get the
funding? You can leave your city and
take a big risk and go to Bangalore but
there's no guarantee that you'll be
introduced to the right people. And if
you get introduced to the right people,
there's no guarantee that they will give
you the right amount of money and all
that. So we don't have this system in
India that uh ensures success like what
you have in Silicon Valley. Silicon
Valley is a place where you will get
funding if you have have the right ideas
and so on. You just have to go and talk.
You go and knock on doors. You know, as
long as you have the right idea, you'll
it'll work. And they're okay in the US
with failure. They are okay with high
amounts of risk. In India, nobody likes
failure. You fail once, it's like you're
become you become radioactive.
In the US, it's okay to fail. Okay, try
again. Try again and eventually if
you're good enough, you'll succeed. So,
all of these issues are the you know are
responsible for India having failed to
develop great products and of course the
ease of doing business. That's another
huge issue in India allegedly.
huge issue
you want to start a company get just
getting a GST registration is such a
headache right and there are all kinds
of other issues that come in the way so
it demoralizes people so too many
problems in the country okay Mr. SA
says, "What were USRussia relations
preworld war II? Uh, was there an event
that created enemies created enemies
after World War II or did rivalry arise
naturally from the two superpowers?
USRussia relations preWorld War II?"
Nothing significant as far as I can
tell. Uh, the Americans in the 19th
century purchased Alaska from Russia.
And at that time, America did not see
Russia as a problem. I mean when the
whoever the president was it was called
his folly or something. So when that guy
went ahead with this purchase of Alaska
for a significant hefty amount of money
taking Alaska giving money to Russia it
was called stupidity. It was called his
folly. Right? So the Americans they did
not see the Russian presence in the
northern part of North America as a
problem. So the US and Russia did not
have a hostile relationship at that
time.
uh even during the first world war the
Americans were not worried about Russia.
It's only after World War II that they
became worried about Russia because
Russia developed this massive massive
industrial base and a massive military
base. Tremendous millions and millions
of soldiers and so on. So that's what
set off alarm bells in the US. Stalin
had transformed this almost defeated
country into a massive industrial
superpower with massive industrial base,
massive military base and huge standing
army.
And uh yeah that that was that was what
made Russia a superpower. So so after
Russia's success in the second world war
it is essentially Russia that defeated
the thud Nazi Germany. That's when the
US decided that yeah Russia is now the
next problem.
Anonymous scientist says when once
visited India Pakistan did pelgam and
now when Mutaki is in India Pakistan
attacked Kabul not a coincidence.
probably not there are no coincidences
in geopolitics when Pakistan launches an
air strike on Kabul it's Pakistan is
sending a message to the Afghan
government to the Taliban government and
if it comes at the time when the Taliban
foreign minister is in India obviously
it's a message to to the the AANS that
you can go and you know make friends
with India but it will cost you that
sort of thing and Pakistan obviously is
a lap dog it's a lap dog of whom of the
United
So there are no coincidences. I'm sure
it's all interconnected, interrelated
and we just have to understand what what
messages are being sent and to whom.
Uh Kiran says Venezuela lop leader of
leader of parliament lop whatever um
received Nobel Peace Prize is deep state
behind the prize since American
companies faced losses by left in
Venezuela.
The US is the deep state behind this
prize. Of course it is. Yeah. Of course.
The Nobel Peace Prize is a political
prize. It's given for as a reward for
services rendered or to prop up a person
as a as a person of eminence and
prominence for for future services to be
rendered to the empire. So this lady who
has been awarded the peace prize uh she
is the Venezuelan equivalent of Muhammad
Yinus.
Muhammad Inus was this guy who who ran
this grain bank thing in in Bangladesh
and he used to charge tremendous amounts
of u you know money for little loans and
all that and they would collect the
money back no matter what happened. Very
hard-handed thing. Um so he was he
wasn't exactly good for his people but
they they gave him the Nobel prize which
which has turned him into some kind of
great saint in the eyes of the of the
Bangladeshes
and now he has been weaponized in in in
this manner that after Shik Hazina was
ousted the Bangladesh is now being run
by a military government but to give it
legitimacy you have put a Nobel Prize
winner as the chief adviser. Ah all
legitimate all good now. Where's the
democracy by the way? No democracy
anyway. So they the Americans probably
want to do a regime change operation in
Venezuela now and grab all the oil. Why
have a you know a third world country
control so much oil in Latin America? We
should have it. So it looks like uh the
Americans are planning a regime change
operation and whenever it happens they
will install this lady as the as the
puppet leader or something.
So yes that's the deal.
Adi Aayou says your take on intercast
marriage all all around the country to
unite the country and end castism and
eventually end reservations. We are
discussing geopolitics. Sir, today I
will not discuss other things. You can
ask this question some other time. Today
we discussing geopolitics. This has
nothing to do with geopolitics. I
apologize but I've made it very clear.
This is a geopolitics super chat
episode. Please look at the title of the
episode. So we discuss geopolitics
today. I apologize but I can't take this
question right now. Shauna Kokate.
Shauna Kok. Shaak. Thank you so much.
Thank you so much. Very nice of you.
Thank you.
Gapati says uh CIA agent James Watson,
US Army major was arrested in Bwandi,
okay, Maharashtra, for illegal
conversion activities. Not the first
time the Yanks are causing trouble. 2611
was CIA Masajob. I don't know about
that. Okay, I I I
don't know about that. Uh is the
government of India taking the
Anglo-Saxon threat seriously? I'm sure
it is. So this James Watson, I have not
not heard of this news, but okay. So
it's no surprise that these things
happen.
There are all these uh
intelligence agents or whatever you want
to call them who come to India on
tourist visas and then they go around
doing conversions
which is completely illegal.
So I'm glad that if this has happened
then it's good. James Watson Bwandi.
Let's let's quickly Google this shall
we? Let's uh Google this. James Watson
Bandi.
James
Watson Bwande
US national arrested in Maharasha for
illegal religious fate of US citizen
uncertain
allegedly attempting to convert
villagers.
Vivi police arrest 58-year-old American
citizen. Hinduism is based on
superstition superstition. Why don't you
go back to your country and do mind your
own business?
So yeah, so obviously all of this is uh
see what they want to achieve is that
they want to achieve industrial scale
convergence in India to make Indians
move away from their culture and their
their civilizational framework and uh
and start following a certain foreign
religion. And that certain fallen
religion has always had the effect of
turning people
uh of of of
it has had the effect of the people who
convert to that religion that those
people they very rapidly develop extr
territorial extr territorial loyalties
they stop being loyal to their country
and their culture. The Japanese have
written about this. The Chinese have
written about this in the 19th century
and and before that. So it's well known
what happens when people convert to a
certain foreign religion. So that's what
so that religion is being used as a
weapon against India so that you they
can create a fifth column in the
country. So uh I'm glad the that the
person was arrested. I hope that that
person will actually be imprisoned and
not extradited back to the US you know
spend a few years u enjoying India's
hospitality that sort of thing. Is the
government of India taking the
Anglo-Saxon threat seriously? Look, it's
not an Anglo-Saxon threat. It's it's a
it's an American threat. The the the
objective is to fragment India. Now, if
I was the US, I would want to do the
same thing, of course, but since we are
India, we have to play defense. So, it's
not exactly Anglo-Saxon or whatever, but
it is what it is. So, I hope the
government of India is taking it
seriously, but I'm not sure it is
entirely taking it seriously. Um ideally
the we should end all attempts to
convert a single even a single person in
the country. End all conversion
activities.
Um but yeah okay
MK says earlier you said Modi may
vasalize India to Trump. I have
discussed all kinds of scenarios. So
what's the problem? I discuss all kinds
of scenarios.
Field strong men says geography is the
most important factor in geopolitics.
What if Russia had two oceans on both
sides? I was about to ask that. What if
what exactly you asking? The most
important factor in geopolitics is it
geography? It's one of the most
important factors. What if Russia had
two oceans on two sides? I was about to
ask what if India discovered gunpowder
first,
but on Wednesday you shocked me when you
said that we actually were. We did have
discovered gunpowder before China. It's
well known but it's not wellnown. It's
suppressed. It is suppressed. It was
called Agnura
and we had it before China. Uh but but
that that if you'll ask Wikipedia, if
you ask Chat GPT, if you ask Google,
they will say China and they will say
that you are doing conspiracy nonsense.
So that's how it has been suppressed.
Now that's a whole different story. Now
geography is the most important factor
in geopolit. It's one of the most
important factors and every nation is a
prisoner of its own geography. You can't
escape that. What if Russia had two
oceans on two sides? It would have been
tremendously beneficial for Russia for
sure, right? Because then they would
have the ability to easily access
various oceans. Right now, it's
difficult for them to access the
Atlantic Ocean, they have to go through
various choke points that are controlled
by their adversaries. Even when it comes
to the eastern
ocean, the Pacific Ocean from from
Russia's perspective, if they want to
send the fleet from Vladivosto out into
the Pacific, they have to pass through
uh US occupied choke points in Japan. So
the US knows exactly what the Russians
are doing. That's the deal. So yeah,
Russia is constrained by that. Even
China is constrained by the three island
trains and so on. And that's where India
has a massive advantage. But we don't
we don't take advantage of that
advantage.
Honak Koker says, "How is it possible
for Poland to firmly say that we will
not take any refugees despite being part
of the European Union because they have
a strong leader?" And the leader
actually seems to care about the country
and the people and the long-term future
of the country. So, it's entirely
possible for this to happen and maybe
it's dangerous for a for a leader to do
that. So, right now I I'm so I suppose
they're paying a fine, a daily fine for
not taking refugees and so on. So the
point is the question is what does
Poland benefit from being part of the
EU?
Maybe there are benefits but there are
these huge problems and constraints
right
um so it's possible any nation can say
no technically and some nations actually
do that Poland and Hungary both refuse
to take uh take refugees
uh but you know Poland is made to pay a
daily fine of several million dollars
every day several at least a million
dollars per day for not accepting the
demands of Brussels to harbor these
horrific refugees in their in their
territory.
AJ Sharma says at 24 nearly a decade in
Deutsland, Germany capped pay, fake
pensions, dumb youth. Even if the US
controls EU, they share roots. Why
collapse their own race?
Why collapse their own race? That's
quite a question you asked here.
Yeah, the the Americans, the
Anglo-Saxons, they have close blood
relations with the Germans for sure.
English after all is a Germanic
language. The Anglo-Saxons, the Saxony
is in Germany. That's where the Saxons
came from and invaded and conquered
England. And the Angles also came from
Anglia or whatever it was part of
Germany. So the Anglo-Saxons are
Germanic people. And why are they
destroying Germany now?
Yeah. Well,
yeah, that's a good question. Why
collapse your own race? Why destroy
Europe, the place you you all came from?
Yeah. Beats me. Beats me. Why would the
Americans do that? What do they gain
from that? One possibility is that they
no longer care about race. They only
care about the United States should rule
the world and Europe should be
de-industrialized and and messed up so
badly that it can never challenge the
United States ever
because Germany is the one nation that
challenged the United States in in the
1930s and 1940s, right? The Second World
War and Germany was very powerful. they
had a tremendous work ethic and
tremendously high standards
and uh that's something that I'm sure
concerns the Americans. So maybe the
reason is that they don't want to see
the the birth of a fudge sometime in the
future whenever it may happen and they
don't want the Germans to be in any way
positioned to in the future create a
third reich. So what was the basis of
the third reich? It was the concept of
the uber folk. The Germans are the uber
bench, the the master race, right?
Destroy the race. Then there is no
question of a master race and there's no
question of fourth,
right? So maybe that's the thinking, the
logic, the rationale behind it perhaps.
Or maybe there's something else behind
it. Well,
okay. Adi says, "I'm tired of seeing my
friends going to college and be becoming
anti-Hindu leftists with absolutely no
geopolitical knowledge."
We all are tired of that. But to to
ensure that this doesn't happen and keep
happening, we will need to have
educational reforms in the country and
the government seems to be absolutely
uninterested in that.
I the government wants to do
infrastructure development the
government wants to do economic
development or to a certain level all
that but if you don't solve the problems
then eventually the whole country will
will move away from its own culture so
who and and and then the Bangladeshi
problem so eventually you're building
all this infrastructure this economy and
all but you're handing it over to whom
that's the question what are you doing
all this for if you want fix these
issues But the government seems to have
absolutely no intention of fixing these
issues which is frustrating. But what
can I say now?
Prattana says did India oppose the US in
a Bagram case by improving relations
with the Afghan Taliban? Is India U
helping the US by keeping China out or
is Pakistan working for the US? Pakistan
is working for the US. First of all,
please be very clear about that.
Pakistan became a US vasal in the year
2022 when Imran Khan was ousted and
whoever is currently the prime minister
was brought to power. Shabbaz Sharif
he's a US sto he's a puppet. Okay. And
Pakistan is now selling its resources to
the Americans. Last time when Shabbaz
Sharif and that Munir fellow they went
to the white house and they were you
know hosted by Trump they they came with
a box of rare earths and and minerals
and showed it to Trump see this is what
you get this is what we will tell you
but you have to line our pockets that
sort of thing so the Pakistanis are in
America's hands they are no longer
aligned with China
um so yeah first of all Pakistan is
working for the US secondly Is India
helping the US by keeping China out of
Afghanistan? Not quite. No, this has
nothing to do with China or the US. Did
India oppose a US base in Bram by
Did India oppose a US base in Bram?
India has kept quiet about this.
India has has not expressed any opinions
about Bagram base. I have not seen any
uh statements from India's ministry of
external affairs or any other government
officials about Bagram.
So I have personally not seen that. So
as far as I know India is staying out of
this matter. It's a bilateral matter
between the US and Afghanistan. Uh by
improving relations with Afghan Taliban
is India helping the US by keeping China
out?
I don't think so.
Is China keep being kept out? We'll see
about that. Uh as far as I know, China
may have given recognition to the to the
to the Taliban. Russia certainly has.
So I'm not sure we are keeping China out
and helping the US. I think it's a
bilateral thing we are doing with
Afghanistan and Afghanistan also has
good relations with China and Russia as
well. So it's once again you see the
three letters once again here R I.
Uh so that's what I can say as of now
the way situations the situation is
evolving. I don't think India is doing
anything to keep China out of
Afghanistan for sure. Anish says big
fan. Thank you sir. Thank you. Uh being
NRI what can we do to report news that
are India biased says one side story to
show India's down I report APL news.
Okay let me see what is APL news. Let's
see uh what is AP uh
news?
American president lines. Is that what
APL News?
Uh, okay. Maybe this is the one.
Anyway, uh so you are an NRI
and what can you do as a reporter
uh to report news that are
India biased
that says one side story to show India
down what you should do as a journalist
is to show balanced news
and if somebody is running anti-India
narratives and propaganda you can debunk
that using facts.
So it is true that India right now is
facing this barrage of anti-India
propaganda all across uh the media
various news outlets, media outlets big
and small and also across social media
as we know very well. So India is
currently the the most uh kind of you
know most targeted nation currently in
the in the western media. Um so in case
you are invest media what you can do is
debunk the misinformation with facts.
Um
that's that's the best you can do. As a
journalist, you need to have your own
code of morality and ethics. And as a
journalist, you actually actually you're
duty bound to present factual and
balanced news. But of course, that is
all theoretical. Today no one does that.
And I understand that totally fine
because journalism has now become
a tool of propaganda. Uh if you work for
any media outlet, you will have to do
whatever the media outlet tells you, the
bosses tell you. And the bosses will do
whatever whoever is paying them
tells them to do. That's how it works.
So essentially, if you want to do
something about the situation, you
should report factual and balanced news
and whatever misinformation is being
spread, what to whatever extent is
possible for you, you should debunk that
using actual facts. That's what you
should do. All right, sir. All the best.
Great job. Keep going.
6P70 Delta says some people say Modi has
made India aligned to the US and follows
US orders and many of them simp for
China a lot. What's my opinion on such
people in their wild slaves? Is India
aligned with the US?
The US is very upset with India.
The US wanted a trade deal very
favorable to the US. Right? They had
given us a deadline of god knows what
what what month was it. I forget now
what month it was
um
June, July, whatever. And we refused to
go along with the American imposed
deadline. We said that a trade deal if
it happens has to be balanced. It has to
benefit both countries. It cannot simply
benefit you. What the Americans wanted
is that India should open up its entire
market
to American imports
with with zero tariffs. So America
should be allowed to export whatever it
wants to India. flood the Indian market
without incurring any tariffs. India
should also open up its agricultural
sector to American exports so that
America can export their horrific dairy
products and their horrific GMO organ
organism agricultural exports into India
which will make Indians diabetic and as
sick as the Americans and it will
destroy India's agricultural sector,
India's farm sector. That's what the
Americans wanted. Modi has refused to do
that. The Americans are extremely upset
about that. That's why they have imposed
50% tariffs on India, right?
Does it look like India is aligned with
the US? It's not. I mean, the facts are
the facts, right? India follows US
orders.
Where does India follow US orders? Come
on.
We blasted Pakistan in Operation Zindur.
The Americans once again were very upset
with that. Is that India following US
orders? Trump said that I negotiated the
se the ceasefire. India has refused to
accept this lie. India has pointed out
that it's a lie multiple times. Does it
look like India is following US orders?
So people will say whatever they want.
They will listen to their favorite
YouTuber or influencer
and they will uh absorb whatever
nonsense is is being pedled over there.
So what can I say about that such
people? What's my opinion? I have no
opinion about them. I don't think about
such people. And the same for China and
so on.
Pratt Dhana says consequences of US base
in Pakistan if it happens.
Uh consequences of a US base in
Pakistan. It will mean that the US gets
more power projection capabilities in
our area. Let's take a look at the map.
Okay, we haven't opened the map yet
today. Well, here is here's where we do
it.
So let's say the US acquires a base in
Pakistan. Let's say um
let's say somewhere in the Macakran
coast region you know near Guadada or
whatever.
So if they acquire a base here for
example on the coastline they will be
able to uh
to use it as a naval base. So American
warships could could dock there whether
it is destroyers or submarines or
aircraft carriers or whatever depends to
be seen. Remains to be seen but they'll
be able to dock there. That's number
one. And if they also acquire an an air
base kind of facility then they'll be
able to project power from this region
along a very wide area. The thing is
that the Americans already have various
air bases. For example, uh if you go to
Qatar, then uh one second, let us
yeah, they have this one here, Abu
Naklah,
which the Americans essentially operate.
If you look at these aircraft here,
uh you will see very distinctive
American aircraft over here. So the
Americans already have power projection
capabilities in the region. See, Qatar
is not really far away from the
subcontinent. They also have Diego
Garcia U over here. If you look here,
you will find that they have massive
basier which can which is not only a
naval base but also an air base. See
here.
So they have the kind of power
projection capabilities that they need
in the region to be able to let's say
threaten if required India and other
countries in the region. Omar you know
Qatar gives them that ability
do Garcia gives them that ability and if
they want more of that they can acquire
a base in Pakistan so from Pakistan
they'll be able to project more power if
and when required for example if they
want to take down the Iranian regime in
the future they could do it from
multiple locations from Qatar from
Pakistan and Israel of course could also
get involved and so on. So it gives them
more options. If they want to let's say
target the Taliban for whatever reason,
they can do it from Pakistan. If they
want to target India for whatever
reason, they can also do it from
Pakistan. Right? So these are the
consequences of a US base in Pakistan if
it happens. It gives America more
options for projecting power and it
allows them to keep an eye on Iran,
Afghanistan and India and possibly
threaten all three countries if
required.
Kajuru Beta Thornne says, "What would
you say are the most propagandized
people in the world today that believe
the most falsehoods?" Indians.
Indians, the Chinese, the Americans,
Europeans, Russians, Indians,
Pakistanis, and North Koreans.
See, first of all, I would say Indians
are super propagandized. Indians live in
delusional La La Land.
So, Indians are definitely
near the very top of the list. Americans
are also super propagandized. Their own
media propagandizes them. They believe
all kinds of weird stuff. Okay?
Americans have no understanding of the
world. If you ever go to the US and you
meet people who live in not in New York
City or Washington DC something, but in
regular towns and in small cities and
all, you will find that they have no
understanding of what is beyond their
nose. Essentially,
if you ask them to locate, let's say,
Poland on a map, they will have no idea
how to locate Poland. If you ask them to
locate Papa New Guinea, they will have
no way of doing it. They will even
struggle to locate India or China or
Russia on a map. And uh they will not
know what's happening in the world. So
they they are super like you know
Americans are also super propagandized
of of course with social media and all
it's it's it's more now the Chinese of
course they will have they will to some
extent be propagandized by their
government Europeans uh
the Japanese are propagandized they
believe in peace they believe uh
whatever is taught in their education
system North Korea I'm sure there's
propaganda Pakistanis are of course
worse than a worse than Indians for sure
Pakistan is Russians I'm not sure about
what's the situation in Russia so
everybody is victim to some forms of
propaganda here and there but some of
the most propagandist people in the
world are Indians Pakistanis North
Koreans for sure even Americans
Europeans also everyone's propaganda I
don't know whom to rate the highest
Indians are deluded Indians live in
delusions they live in Lalands Indians
believe that we are like like you know
30 minutes away from being a superpower
and we are visual guru we are neither a
vishwag guru nor a superpower we'll not
be a superpower even in 2050
but we should be a great power by 2050
that's why that's what we should work
towards
and vishwaguru please so all see this is
all propaganda it's nonsense India is a
land of slogans slogan slogan slogan
every day new slogan comes up and we all
believes that the slogans
yeah
6P70
delta says a Ukrainian outlet claims
that Russia has is withdrawn Asian
ethnicities like Buryats from its
umbrella.
From its what? Umbrella. War. What is
What is that that symbol?
From its war army. Okay. Uh Russia is
withdrawing Asian ethnicities like
Buryas from its army as they are weaker
than Ukrainian soldiers. Is it true or
is it true or is it racist neo-Nazi
propaganda?
I am not aware of the Russian
government withdrawing
any
any such u any specific ethnicities from
the armed forces. I'm not aware of that.
I think all I think that's nonsense.
Russia would not do that. I don't think
so. Uh the buryats, who are the buryats?
Okay, first of all, if you are
discussing the buryats, who are the
buryats?
The Buryats are descendants of Mongols.
You really think Mongols are weaker than
Ukrainians?
Do you know? So I'm just saying I'm not
saying to you specifically the person
who asked the question, but do we know
the history of Mongolia?
Do we think Mongols are weak?
This is utter nonsense clearly.
Yeah. If you if you wanted to double
check who the Buryats are, let's do it.
I said that they're descendants of
Mongols, right?
Buryats. Who are the Buryats? Ethnic
group. Buryat language. The the Yakuts.
Uh, Buryat's ancestry.
Buryat's ancestry. What is their
ancestry? See, Mongolic speaking nomadic
tribes. Okay. Their ancestry is
Mongolic. Mongol. So my point is are the
Ukrainians if if they claiming this are
they saying that Mongols are weaker than
Ukrainians? Do they not know anything
about their own history? Huh?
Okay. So this is a joke clearly. Don't
take it seriously. Anamalai. Thank you
so much sir. Thank you very much. Really
appreciate that.
Ah my favorite my favorite person is
back. James James James is back.
Your ancient monuments are small,
fragile.
Europe builds ginormous monuments,
colored clone, cathedral, colosum.
We even shaped the modern era
cheerio.
Yes, our ancient monuments are small and
fragile.
But you see, first of all, let's address
the first point that you're talking
about. H our ancient monuments are small
and fragile. We have monuments sitting
at the bottom of the sea of the ocean
for about 10,000 years. H the Gulf of
Kat archaeological complex Dara Gulf of
Kabat archaeological complex is about 10
or 11,000 years old. It's a network of
cities laid out in grid structure that's
sitting at the bottom of the ocean for
about 10,000 years since the last
glacial period.
Fragile, how come it's still there?
Darka is still there. Our monuments, our
ancient monuments, small, fragile, we
have pretty colossal architecture in
some some parts of India. The rest was
destroyed by the Turks. Okay. Now, when
it comes to monuments, when it comes to
colossal monuments, these colossal
monuments have to serve some function in
society, right? See, for example, take
the take the pyramids of Egypt,
gigantic
mega monuments. How did these gigantic
mega monuments that took so much slave
labor to build, how did this serve
society?
How a monument has to serve society?
Anything that is constructed has to
serve society. In India, we had this
grand temples that actually served
society. They did not simply function as
a place of spiritual and religious
solace or whatever. They also functioned
as centers of education. they had a
central role in society and in in
preparing the future generations of
society.
So our in India our monuments were
functional monuments and we had a great
sense of beauty and aesthetics. Even
small monuments if you see how
beautifully intricately they were carved
it made
the country so beautiful right um yes
Europe builds ginormous monuments
cathedral you have something in
Barcelona and so on. What purpose does
it serve to society? And where did the
money come from? The colossium. Good.
The colossium was about, you know,
keeping the the rebel occupied.
Yeah. Keeping the rebel occupied while
while the politicians do their thing
and so on. We shape the modern era. See,
the modern era that you're talking about
is the era of colonization and foreign
occupation by the Europeans and
destruction of non-European societies
and cultures and plundering these
cultures and societies and enriching
Europe as a consequence. And once so
much money and and treasure and gold and
so much flows in, you've got to do
something with it. So you build big
things. So it's a monument to uh 500
years of European uh
rapesious oppression of the world and
I'm glad that era is now ending when it
comes to the UK
uh Londonistan Britainistan that's what
you are becoming and it is now a faith
accompli
okay it's done you're done in the next
few years you're going to be in Islamic
Republic and I I congratulate the Muslim
uh people of Britain for having won.
You've already won. Enjoy. So enjoy what
happens to those monuments
after the takeover. Enjoy that.
Bijuai says
uh do you think CIA deep state had any
role in the dissolution of Yes.
Or does the entire credit go to to Mr.
Gorbacha? Did the CIA and deep state
have any role in the dissolution of the
USSR or does the entire credit go to Mr.
Gorbachov? Can this happen to China? Uh
the entire credit credit cannot go to
Mr. Gorbachov, the Americans, the CIA,
deep state, whatever you want to call
it. They also played a big role in this
in in putting all the pieces in place
and you know possibly reaching out to
Mr. Gorbacho. Not sure. I'm just saying.
So it's not entirely Mr. Gorbacho. The
Americans also tightened the news on
around the Russians. The Russians had
their own problems, internal problems.
Their standards were declining,
dropping. There was too much corruption.
There was too much decay in Russia. And
then Gorbachev was the guy who put the
final nails in the coffin. But with the
help of the US. So I would not say it's
entirely Gorbachev who takes the credit.
The Americans also take the credit. And
they they the Americans won.
Can the same happen in China? It's less
likely for that to happen in China. For
that to happen in China, China's
standards need to drop, which is not
happening. And you need a leader like
Gorbachina which you don't have right
now. Uh in the future it could happen.
It could happen in the future but right
now it's not anywhere close to
happening. Okay. Pratiba says good
evening. Well good evening. Thank you
very much. Happy advance. Okay. Thank
you so much. I thought you were going to
ask question. Thank you so much. I
really appreciate that. Really very
much. I do appreciate that. Thank you
very much ma'am. Thank you so much.
67 6P70 Delta says in response to India
US wanting to have
US military base in India
AIM told cases of US soldiers abusing
Japanese girls being tried in US courts
not Japanese courts and not held guilty
most of the time is being vasal so bad
if you are a vasal
you have to face regular humiliation
what's h yeah I The behavior of American
troops who occupy Japan is abominable.
Abominable. Look it up. Look at look at
Okinawa protests against US. Uh let's
see. Okay.
Oki Nawa
protests
against
US military.
US military abuse for example. I don't
want to use that word.
Okay. Endured a history of crimes
spanning decades. See sexual assault
case in Okinawa. It's it's regular. It's
routine. And these soldiers, these
American occup occupation soldiers who
do this to Japanese girls and women,
they are not tried in Japanese courts.
They'll be tried in US courts and
they'll be punished by the US. And
usually the punishment is a slap on the
wrist. Typically, nothing much more than
that. I mean what the Americans did in
Iraq
in various prisons. Okay, I don't even
even want to discuss that. That's how
horrific it is. What happened? How badly
were the were the perpetrators punished?
Very light punishments.
Uh so yeah, being a vasal is terrible.
If you have a good overlord, if you are
a vasal to a good overlord, then you may
not be humiliated that much. You of
course have to endure some humiliation,
some ritual humiliation at least.
But if you have if you are the vasal of
a nasty overlord, you face all kinds of
issues such as this. What what the
Japanese face and there's nothing they
can do about it. Right.
Teen talks Dharma says, "You said
Taliban is supported by the US and
Pakistan and also US puppet. I must have
said that 5 years ago, sir.
When did I say that? I must have said
that 5 years ago or something. The world
is changing sir. The world is changing
very rapidly. Every two weeks the
situation changes now.
Right?
I must have discussed this. God knows
when. The Taliban is no one's puppet
today.
Okay. Let's think about it clearly.
Um it is true that there are allegations
that the Taliban is receiving a stipend
of about between 30 to $100 million in
cash every week from the US.
It is so in case that is true
uh see the Taliban was given power by
the US after the accord the negotiations
and the accord in DHA.
Um and there were secret clauses to this
deal to this accord which have not been
released to the public. So clearly there
is some kind of understanding or
agreement between the Taliban and the US
that the Taliban will play some kind of
role in the region that will be
beneficial to the US. Most likely
keeping China out
most likely nothing beyond that. and and
and and in exchange for that the
Americans are paying them a certain
amount of money every week.
So yeah to that extent you could say
there is some US role in Taliban in in
the Taliban and the Afghanistan
relationship. Pakistan also is a US
puppet. True. So is the m if the master
is same then why fight? Okay, great
question. Now I understand what you're
asking. If the master is the same then
why fight? So, so Pakistan is a US
wasal. Taliban has an understanding and
some kind of deal with the US and they
are performing some kind of service that
the Americans want and that's why the
Americans are paying them. So then why
should the two fight? Because the
Taliban is not a vasal. Pakistan is
the Taliban has an understanding of some
kind, some secret understanding of some
kind with the US, but not a vasal hood
relationship.
The US was done with Afghanistan. They
were done with their occupation of
Afghanistan 20 years. They did and they
said time's up now. We should leave. We
should not waste any more time,
resources or energy over here. We'll
hand over to the Taliban and they will
play a certain role for us. That's it.
So the Taliban is an independent
sovereign government
mostly sovereign and they are not
American vasals. Pakistan is
and the Americans are right now
pressurizing the Taliban also to get the
Bram air base and possibly to revitalize
Afghanistan to the US and the Taliban
doesn't want that. The Taliban are
pashon nationalists and for them it is
humiliation to be someone's vasal and
that's why they fought so many years
decades they fought so that they don't
have to be anyone's vasal and most
likely the agreement that the they have
with the US the secret agreement it is
not a wasallowed agreement which is why
the Taliban are now you know fighting
the Pakistanis
um and the Pakistanis are hitting the
Taliban with Americanmade weapons F-16s
and whatnot
So the Taliban don't recognize the US as
a master. The Pakistanis are lap dogs of
the US. Very big difference. The Taliban
have this big issue with Pakistan. First
of all, terrorism, constant terrorism.
And secondly, territorial dispute.
The the Afghans claim a big chunk of
Pakistani territory. So that's the deal.
Abishek Shivasu says your views in Amit
Sha's statement on rising Muslim
population. I have no state no views on
this.
Anamalai says how to stop India from
becoming like Londonistan where civil
war is in is incoming MMA training for
RSS to prevent future partition or civil
war in India. I am discussing
geopolitics sir. We'll discuss
geopolitics. We'll not discuss internal
matters of India in this episode and I
generally don't discuss these issues
anyway. So apologies but I can't take
this question. Adi Aayu says Bihar
stands on the edge of fall my
once again this is not a geopolitics
question Congress RJD this is internal
politics which I don't have any
significant understanding of so I can't
take this question please ask questions
about geopolitics I implore you because
I will not take other questions
fast snail says rumor has it that there
was a taskant like the possibility of a
tashandlike situation at this Shangai
Cooperation Organization summit in
Russia saved it from happening. Hard to
believe. Do you buy that? I am not sure.
Whoever has put out this theory, how do
they know this?
How do they know it? Were they present
in Shangghai or or or at the summit?
Mr. Modi said something in some public
appearance
that are you clapping because I'm here
or are you clapping because I was able
to come back or something like that. I'm
not sure if it means what is being,
you know, what it's being uh assumed to
mean. I'm not sure about that. I
personally have no evidence that there
was any plan or plot by by an external
power to assassinate Mr. Modi. I've
heard of this rumor, but this rumor has
been presented as a story without any
evidence whatsoever. The only evidence,
circumstantial evidence that is given is
that Mr. Putin uh invited Mr. Modi into
his his car his limousine and they drove
around for about 45 minutes and it is
being said that Mr. Putin did this so
that Mr. Modi is not targeted at that
time
apparently Mr. The was aware there was
some plan that's that's the claim that
is being made. Do we have any evidence
of this? We don't have any evidence of
it. So what can I say? I I will say that
this is a story without any evidence. So
what can be claimed without evidence can
also be dismissed without evidence. I'm
not saying it's not possible. I'm saying
there is no evidence. So I can't discuss
further beyond that.
Godliness says what's the f future of
Gaza after the so-called ceasefire? Will
it sustain or is it an everlasting war?
This is now over. I think
um
this ceasefire is essentially the deal
demilitarization of Hamas. Trump has
given Hamas a final ultimatum.
Agree to my demands. Put down your
weapons. You can stay in Gaza if you
want. You can leave to some other
country if you want. That's your choice.
We will not stop you. But this is it.
And if you don't agree to this, I'm
giving permission to Netanyahu to
completely flatten Gaza and nobody will
survive. So that was the ultimatum Trump
gave them and they have accepted it
because they know that this is it. If
they don't agree, they they finished.
They'll be vaporized.
So what happens now is that they will
hand over or if they have already hand
over I'm not sure but they will hand
over all the hostages
and then uh they will demilitarize then
the Israeli
military will create a cordon around
Gaza then some external government will
come in and and take over maybe it is
fatah maybe it is some international um
prominent people who will be part of
this government this this temporary
government that will govern Gaza and
then Gaza will be redeveloped in some
way. Maybe Trump towers will come up
over there or maybe casinos will come up
over there or something, but Gaza is
essentially done. And what this
ceasefire means that is is that Israel
has won and they will re reframe and
reshape Gaza in whatever way they want.
That's essentially what it means. So
it's a it's a victory for Israel. This
is that's what the ceasefire means.
66p70
delta says Putin has set a goal this
year to raise Russia's TFR to 2.1 by
2030. Will he be successful? Also
regarding last live stream comment,
please search images of BRV yacht yacht
very similar to my photo in the dark.
Okay, let's search for bridge yacht,
shall we?
Brev yacht.
BR
Nev
bra navat.
[Laughter]
Okay. He looks like me, does he? I don't
see it, but okay. If you say so.
Okay, that looks like him with his
family.
Very nice. All right. All right. Okay.
So, now let's come to the question.
Let's come to the question. Uh Putin has
set a goal. So let let's first of all
find out what is Russia's TFR right now,
shall we? Uh Russia TFR
2025. What is it? It's 1.83 children per
woman.
Can it be brought up to 2.1 by 2030? I
suppose with the right kinds of
incentives and whatnot, it is it is
possible. I think it'll be challenging
to bring up the TFR to that, but it's
certainly possible. So, you have to ask
yourself, what is it that brings the TFR
down? When people are overworked,
when they're exhausted by working too
hard and too much, too many hours, then
they can't procreate.
Secondly, if it's very expensive to
raise children, if the education is
super expensive, if there are tremendous
hurdles in the way of getting good
education, if uh if healthcare is
expensive, then all of those factors
will have people will will force people
to have less children or to have no
children at all. So if you and and and
you know if if the women are working
and if when they deliver a child they
they are forced to get back to work in
let's say 4 weeks or whatever it is then
that's a huge problem right who will
take care of the child in in situations
where you have nuclear families it's a
huge problem so so to bring the TFR up
you have to first of all ensure that
people are not overworked people have a
balanced lifestyle you work 8 hours and
then spend the rest of the day doing
whatever you
Right? Don't don't work 10 hours, 12
hours, 14 hours a day like is the norm
in India these days in in the private
sector and whatnot. Right? That's one
thing. So people should not be
overworked. They should not be
exhausted. They should not be mentally
burned out, physically burned out.
Secondly, women when they have children,
when they are pregnant, they should be
given uh time off and uh when they give
birth, they should have I don't know at
least 6 months or something. It's not
good for the economy. Yeah, that's one
perspective you can you can put forth.
But secondly, it will bring up the TFR
if they get that much time downtime to
spend child time with the child and
raise the child at least 6 months maybe
one year. So with the right incentives
and then and then if you make uh for
example education very affordable in
healthcare very affordable then people
will will start having more kids.
So with the right kinds of incentives
and maybe you can give tax breaks to
people who have more more than two
children or something not people maybe
the mother if you have more than two
children you get you you pay no income
tax no you pay no tax whatsoever that
again is an incentive to have having
children more children so by
using the right kinds of incentives it's
certainly possible to bring the TFR up
from two from 1.83 83 to 2.1 certainly
possible. Yeah.
Mr. Sakennena says Switzerland isn't
part of the EU, EA or NATO. Does it make
it a quasai sovereign country or there's
more to it? Um I would say there's more
to it.
Okay. It's a small tiny country, very
beautiful country, very nice people etc.
Okay.
which sits in the middle of all these
big countries
and it's always remained neutral. Well,
until recently, now it's not that
neutral.
For example, it it froze bank accounts
of various Russian government things and
all. So, it's it's no longer that
neutral. But even during the second
world war, for example, Germany was
overr over overrunning all of Europe.
But they decided that we will not touch
Switzerland. We'll leave it alone.
Right? So why was Switzerland given this
preferential treatment? Because
Switzerland plays a role in Europe. It
provides a certain kind of service to
the people of Europe. Whoever you are,
no matter how much money you have, if
you want a safe place to keep the money,
you do it here.
The condition is you don't touch
Switzerland. You stay out of it. You
leave us alone. We'll safeguard your
money. We'll ask no questions. Where did
the money come from?
um who were the original owners of of
the of the treasures and gold that
you're putting here will not ask any
questions. It is safe. We guarantee
that. But you have to leave us alone.
You don't mess with our sovereignty or
territorial integrity. So that's the
deal.
So that is the service has been
providing in exchange for remaining kind
of sovereign. So it is from that
perspective very sovereign. They have a
national defense force. Every uh adult
male now I don't know but maybe women
also I'm not sure used to be men.
Everybody under goes military training.
Every
every few every 3 four years you have to
undergo a few weeks of military
training. Every adult male at least I
know of had a gun in their house which
was provided by the government and
ammunition and they have tunnels and
whatnot across the country where you
know uh the army can be mobilized and
people you know arms ammunition can be
hidden and so on. So they are well
prepared for a possible potential
invasion also if it ever happens. So all
these factors makes kind of a sovereign
country. I would say it's not no country
of that size is entirely sovereign. So
yeah, it kind of makes it a quasi
sovereign country as long as it you know
provides the services that are required.
It will be left alone. That is the deal.
Karthik Arisha says Dalai Lama and his
brother's links with the CI. I am I am
not aware of it sir. I'm not aware. His
brother did write a book about the
noodle maker of Khalim Pong or something
right?
Let's see what is the book called. How
did the the name come to my mind? Noodle
maker of Kalim
Pong.
The noodle maker of Kalim Pong. The
untold story of my struggle for Tibet.
And who wrote the book? Authors Galo
Tundup and Thirstston and so on. So who
is Galot Tundup? The second oldest
brother of the 40th Dalai Lama closest
adviser based in India. So that's that's
what I can tell you. That's as much as I
know. I am not aware of any links with
the CIA so can't comment beyond that. Uh
Devil X537 thank you very much sir first
of all thank you so much big fan thank
you India shows huge huge progress on
paper but the average person's life
doesn't seem to improve much you are
correct
also most politicians kids live abroad
you are again correct why is there such
a gap between real life and reported
progress the reported progress is based
on metrics
GDP what's the growth rate quarter upon
quarter GDP growth rate as long as it's
around 6 6.5 whatever. Well, that is
these are numbers. These are actually
calculated numbers. So these numbers are
real. The reported progress is along
certain metrics. How many kilometers of
highway did we build per day in the last
quarter? So this is those are real
numbers. That's also real progress. How
many kilometers of railway lines did we
lay down per day in the last quarter?
Whatever the number is. And these
numbers are very encouraging. Uh how
many villages electrified in so and so
here? How many villages got gas
connections got got u uh water
connections and blah blah blah all that
stuff. How many kilometers of border
roads have been built per day per the
last quarter and so on. So all these
metrics are real metrics, real progress.
But the question you are asking is very
very appropriate because do any of these
metrics actually
actually in a real way impact the
quality of life of the average person in
India. So we have to ask ourselves what
are the factors that impact the quality
of life. Sure access to running water
fantastic. Sure. Once you get that you
have a certain quality of life. After
that what happens? So electricity you
get it once good. It stays with you.
water, you get it still with you. Uh
toilet connection, what whatever that
means and so on. Uh better highways,
better railways, it's all good, but what
actually impacts the quality of life is
this
uh access to bank accounts. Again, lots
of people did not have that and so on.
But quality of life,
what is the kind of future your children
are going to have?
Do they get good education or do do they
get a rotten education?
If you need a job, are you going to have
to face reservations?
Right? If you need to interface with the
government, are you going to have to
allegedly pay bribes?
If you want to start a business,
you're going to have to are you going to
allegedly have to play to pay bribes?
Are you going to have to pay bribes like
it is alleged at every step of the way
for every piece of permission that you
need? And then will you have to
apparently allegedly pay bribes on an
ongoing basis?
If you are a street vendor, do you
allegedly have to pay pay hafta?
Even if you pay all these things and do
all of this stuff, do you get good roads
or do you get roads with potholes that
are rebuilt every every year so that the
cash flow keeps going?
Do you I mean can you breathe clean air?
Are the cities, towns, villages livable?
Do the municipal corporations even care?
So the metrics that are reported
they don't affect the life of people.
They overall make the country better
slowly gradually.
But what they call achin
is a whole different set of parameters
and there's no change there. There's no
change there. Right?
So the average person's life doesn't
improve much because of that. I would
say that look from 2014 till now I would
say there has been definitely a
qualitative improvement to some extent
in the life of the average Indian
because of all the steps that have been
taken. You can't deny that. But what
people aspired for, none of that has
happened,
right? End to the alleged corruption,
you know, tremendous ease of doing
business, um, you know,
better education system, better living
standards,
you know, better roads in cities, less
pollution. Many of these things haven't
happened and that's the issue. So yeah,
it's it's because of the way the system
is structured.
It is alleged that the entire system
runs on corruption and I've said so many
times that what India needs desperately
is a war on corruption.
So if you were to ask me one factor that
is the reason for this huge gap between
real life and the progress that's
actually happening I would say it's the
alleged corruption that permeates
all branches many many branches
allegedly of u of the system let's let's
call it yeahha
says a couple of months back the Chinese
made allegations s that Starlink can
detect fifth generation jets and warned
Musk not to be emitted on China. What
are my thoughts?
I'm sure it can do much more than that.
I'm sure it can do much more than than
that. Starlink is this network of
thousands of satellites that are in
orbit, low earth satellites.
Is their only purpose to beam internet?
I'm sure they have all kinds of other
sensors and equipment that allows the US
to to monitor what's happening on the
ground on the planet in real time
wherever required
that's why Elon Musk and Starling are so
important to the US right so I am pretty
sure that these satellites have way more
capabilities than what is being told to
us
first of all Starling itself is a
dangerous dangerous thing for the
sovereignty of any nation that is not
not America. Hugely dangerous, hugely
problem problematic. And secondly, these
satellites will have all kinds of
sensors and equipments that will allow
the United States to keep a very close
watch in real time on what's happening
across the world. So, uh, if the Chinese
have made these allegations, I'm not
surprised at all and I completely agree
with them. Completely agree with them.
So maybe they have sensors that can
detect fifth generation fighter planes.
That's also one of the possibilities.
Rashit Shvastav says, "My friend's dad
worked in Japan's intel. His team
reported to the US embassy. He
questioned it, lost his job. Is co just
a CIA extension?" Let me see what is co.
Okay.
Cir O Japan. Before I answer the
question, yeah. Cabinet Intelligence and
Research Office is what Wikipedia says
also knows as Nitro is the national
civilian intelligence agency under the
Japanese cabinet secretariat tasked with
advancing national security blood etc.
Okay. and the cabinet. So if you look at
the Wikipedia page, I am sure it will
not mention the US at all.
But Japan is a country under US
occupation and everything in Japan,
everything of any importance is reported
to the US and it's controlled by the US.
So your friend's dad worked in Japan's
intel in CIR. His team reported to the
US embassy.
He questioned it and lost his job.
Absolutely no surprise whatsoever. Japan
is an occupied nation.
Then the Americans want to ensure that
Japan never ever rises again the way it
rose in the past. Very dangerous. Very
dangerous. So you're going to keep an
eye on all the people of Japan and what
they're doing. Nationalists
nationalistic sentiments need to be
crushed.
So yeah, is CO a CI extension? Most
likely it is. Most likely it is. Yes.
Uh 6 P70 Delta says is KZ
in a tug of war between China and
Russia. Why no map nowadays? KZ is it
Kyrgystan or is it is it Kazakhstan?
Why no map nowadays? Which no map? Let
me see the map. Does Kazakhstan no
longer exist in the map? Let's see
together.
Um in case you're talking about
Kazakhstan, I'm sure Kystan is not that
important. It's a much smaller nation.
So Kazakhstan map is here. Why no map
nowadays? Kyrgystan's map is here.
Kazakhstan is here. North of Kyrgyzstan,
you have Kazakhstan. Very large nation.
Is it in a tug of war between China and
Russia? There's going to be some tug of
war. There's going to be some tug of war
because China is a nation with a with
world's second largest economy and they
want to project power way beyond where
they can today. They are very ambitious
and Kazakhstan and all the central Asian
republics have traditionally been part
of Russia's sphere of influence. So
there's going to be a talk of war in all
these nations between Russia and China
for sure. I'm not sure what you're
asking about about the nom map but yeah
godliness says India's prime minister
happily announced that nine British
universities will will open their campus
in India for higher learning. Certainly
we want our children to be pro-
Anglo-Saxction and for forget about the
gurugul vast. So this is how we become
visual guru I suppose by having other
universities open open their centers in
India. Look I am not opposed to British
universities or American universities or
Australian universities or Chinese
universities or Japanese universities
whoever Russian whatever French
German I am not opposed to any any of
these universities opening campuses in
India.
My question is what will they be
teaching? What courses will they be
offering?
I want them to teach only STEM,
science, technology, educ education and
and what medicine. Is it medicine? I I
want them to teach only science,
technology,
science and technology. I don't want any
of the nonsensical gend gender nonsense
and women's studies and social sciences
to come into India. I don't want them to
teach any of that nonsense.
So what's the deal? Are they going to be
able to decide whatever they want to
teach or will they will we impose
preconditions that these are the
subjects you can teach and these are the
subjects you're not allowed to teach. In
case we giving them a kak blanch that do
whatever you want then we are digging
our own grave in India as a nation with
a severe inferiority complex. So I think
many of our
I don't know government officials
believe this is a fantastic thing for
India. We will have better better
English language education now. I think
it's terrible.
I think we should invest in our own
education system. Anyhow, Vun says, "Is
procurrency the number one invention by
the US? They used it to hire talent, pre
print free money of unimaginable
quantities and fund their R&D
infrastructure. Is this not a scam? US
aid like funds, are they still coming to
India?" I think US aid funds are not
coming to India but the US has so many
other US aid uh alternatives like the
national endowment for democracy and so
many other NOS and whatnot through which
so many of the NGOs on US on on Indian
territory through which funds can be
funneled into India. So the funding for
whatever American projects exist in
India has not stopped at all. Okay. Uh
is procreny the number one invention by
the US?
There are so many number one inventions
for the US. Petrocurrency is one of
those. Yeah. Today the dollar is no
longer a petro dollar. It's a completely
free floating fiat currency with no link
to anything. Not gold, not petroleum,
not anything at all. Uh and yeah,
because they can print free money. They
can print as much as they want. And so
that's why they are able to, you know,
use it to hire talent and uh fund
whatever R&D they're doing. Another
fantastic invention. Let's discuss this
is the H1B visa and the green card
thing. Let me explain what I mean by
that. So if you are a person from let's
say a first world country then your visa
processing times, green card times are
very very quick. Depends on where you're
born. If you're born in let's say Europe
then you get a different amount of you
know the time to process your vis takes
you to process your US visa is very
short and even if you are in line for
green cards you will be given a green
card way ahead of Indians so they make
it very fast for Europeans and people
from first world countries but when it
comes to Indians
if if an Indian is applying for a green
card it'll take them years maybe decades
to get a green card forget about
citizenship even a green card which is
permanent residency and the H-1B visa
program itself is a is a thing that is
like a you know sword hanging over your
neck all the time so what they do is
this they have Indians coming into the
US for studies Indians typically pay
like I don't know 50 lakhs or something
for the studies for a master's degree or
something typically to the US so first
of all all this money comes in then the
Indians who acquire a master's degree or
whatever in the US they want to stay on
because they want to escape the horrors
of India the third worldness of India,
the horrible living standards and the
alleged corruption and the reservations
and all that they want they want to
escape that so the Indians who get a
degree they are desperate to get a job
now in the US okay so the next step is
to search for a job so you get a job
let's say and your employer will sponsor
your visa H1B visa and the visa has to
be renewed every two three years or
whatever it is there is always a sword
hanging over your neck and after a while
you you become eligible for applying for
a green card and that process takes 10
15 years. So Indians who are going
through this process will work super
hard
will work super hard they'll work double
the the intensity of of an American so
that you know there is no blemish on the
record until they get a green card. So
the Americans they get all this free
talent very cheap talent very
hardworking talent just by extending the
green card times and visa times and
keeping the sword hanging over the neck
of Indians. So you see when you are
developing new technologies and all you
need long-term focus on things that may
or may not work
and for that Indians are best because
there is a sword hanging over over the
neck and they'll just keep on working.
So you don't need to hire Americans for
that. You have Indians do that. It's
another fantastic scam the Americans
have have invented. So yeah,
Amisha says Maki visited Deoband. What
are your thoughts? So Deobund this Darul
ulum whatever that institution is it is
the the alma matter of the of Alma
matter of the Taliban Taliban movement
is theobandhi movement
so so makes sense and possibly Mr.
Mutaki would have studied there I'm not
sure did Mr. Mutaki study there? Let's
find out. Let's Google that. Even if he
did not study there, the that that
institution is the the alma mater of the
Taliban. Mut did
did Maki.
Mutaki.
What's his name? Mutaki
study at Deoband.
Did he
seminary history studied and taught?
Okay. I'm not sure who was the first
maana mutaki did. Maana
no ma
ma
mai mutaki studied at the
I'm not sure if he studied there.
Um
yeah that's that's okay but the Taliban
movement is a bundi movement.
So it's like visiting you know visiting
your birthplace kind of thing. That's
what it meant for Mutaki and uh yeah it
has given India some kind of
geopolitical advantage for for once the
existence of this DH ulum seminary in
the Ubant. All right it's okay. Chat DSP
says the current US China trade war
resumption is it t is the tactical for
the up is it a tactical thing for the
upcoming apex summit. How can India
leverage the situation to cut a deal
with the US or is the new containment
strategy too strong?
India can't leverage any of this to cut
a deal with the US. The US the deal the
US wants is a maximalist deal. The US
gets everything. India gets nothing.
That's what the US wants. This situation
cannot be leveraged by India to cut some
kind of deal with the US. The US is very
clear what kind of deal they want and we
are not willing to give it because that
is vasal hood. Uh is this US China trade
war resumption? Is it tactical for
upcoming apex summit?
It's not tactical, it's strategic. The
Chinese have imposed restrictions on the
expose of rare earth minerals which are
critical for the US and the US military
and the US is responding to that by
imposing more tariffs and whatnot. So
it's not a tactical thing, it's a
strategic thing. The Chinese are
leveraging whatever advantage they have.
It it probably has nothing to do with
the apex summit.
Rohan Suna says, I have interacted a lot
with both Ivy League graduates and
Scandinavian PhDs. Ivy League guys are
dumb people but Nordic PhDs are
excellent. What's my take? I haven't
interacted with Nordic PhDs so I can't
say. U look what do I know of
Scandinavian PhDs? I know the Neils Bore
Institute in Copenhagen
which as far as I know has a very high
reputation and in very high standards. U
it was established by Neils Bohar
himself. Beyond that what other PhDs
come out of the out of Scandinavia? I'm
not sure.
uh Ivy League graduates
are they dumb?
I'm not sure if all of them are dumb.
Many of them will be dumb.
Yeah. Uh
if you are an Ivy League product, it
means either you have paid a tremendous
amount of money, your daddy or your
mommy paid a tremendous amount of money
to put you through that or otherwise
maybe you are really really smart. But
once again it depends on the field. If
you are an Ivy League PhD from the field
of physics, well, I will take that
person seriously. But if you're an Ivy
League PhD from the field of some social
science or something, I will I'm pretty
sure that they're going to be dumb
because you can't be dumb and get a
physics PhD from an Ivy League
university, right? Even if your mom or
dad paid paid big money for that, you
can't get a PhD. So, it depends. It
depends.
So, if it's a physics PhD, I will take
them more seriously. If it's a math PhD,
I'll take them more seriously. If it's
from the scientific fields, I'll take
them more seriously. If it's from those
fake fake subjects like home science and
women's studies and social sociology and
whatever else, I
I I will be like, you know, I will not
be surprised if if they dump.
Fast snail says, "Qatar is building air
force station in Idaho.
Will it irk Israel?" It won't irk
Israel. Israel won't care about it.
Israel won't be concerned whatsoever.
Israel is fine. They all understand
what's happening. It's all good.
Okay. B Mandav says China builds a lot
of infrastructure in Tibet. Will it get
freedom ever? Not for the foreseeable
future. Tibet is not getting any freedom
for the foreseeable future. Sadly, it is
what it is. Abida Singh says Wagner
Group SCOP pagers explosion by Mossad
India's Akash system. What tactical and
technological wonders are in store next
for us to observe?
Well, eventually they will reveal what
the UFOs are. The UFOs that fly across
the US appear over cities and whatnot.
You know, are the drones or the UFOs?
What are those things? UAPs, whatever. I
think that's the next technological
wonder for us to understand. you know
someday perhaps they will reveal what it
is. It's probably very high you know
highly advanced uh technology of some
kind. So maybe that's what is the wonder
which will come next for us to observe.
Uh okay unknown user says I see us lead
world US-led world is full of misery in
a hypothetical scenario if India becomes
a global power how should it respond to
harms caused by the US revenge against
the country it leader or its people
if India hypothetically someday becomes
a global power the most powerful nation
we should not take revenge on anybody
if we are in a position where where we
are the leader of the world then we
use it to make the world a better place.
As long as as that doesn't cost us too
much money and doesn't harm us, right?
Don't sacrifice your interest for the
rest of the world, but as long as it
doesn't hurt your interest or harm them
in any way. Make the world a better
place. That's our culture.
Uh how should we respond to harms caused
by the no revenge? I I am not a person
who is vindictive. I am not someone who
would seek revenge. And hopefully
whoever the Indian leader is in this
hypothetical scenario he or she will
also not seek revenge
right just make the world a better place
in whatever way is possible in such a
way that it doesn't hurt our interests
or you know cost us a lot I mean doing
social service can cost you a lot right
so obviously nation civilization comes
first but beyond that if as far as
possible make the world a better place
no revenge and all that
anonymous scientist says will China
Pakistan relations remain stable in the
near future because Pakistan is
completely in the hands of the US. Now
China India will come close
uh China Pakistan relations will remain
stable but not the relationship they had
when they were iron brother brothers
that won't be there. China will not get
access to whatever they were able to
access in Pakistan before 2022.
China is out now. The US is the boss in
Pakistan but relations will remain
stable. China is a pragmatic nation.
China doesn't do boohoo because you you
turn your back on us. Yeah, China is a
is a pragmatic nation. It's not an
emotional nation. So the relationship
will remain stable. Um China, India,
will it come will these two nations come
close? Um the Americans are forcing
India and China to become closer. So
there will be some kind of some kind of
understanding, some kind of cooperation,
some kind of deescalation to some extent
between India and China. But I'm not
optimistic for India and China resolving
all all their issues. So those issues
will remain but beyond that for at least
the next certain period of time whatever
years India and China will lower
the tensions and work together in a
pragmatic way cooperate in wherever
wherever it's possible and whichever way
you know is is is potentially available
to us that's what will happen.
Humar Patel thank you very much sir.
Nobody good name. Thank you very much
sir. Shrat Shuklas says in British rule
it was said Labor Party favored India
and Conservative party tortured us. 70
years later the same story line
Democrats versus the Republican in US.
Does deep state behave the same way as
British crown.
The British the the deep state owns the
And the Republicans versus Democrat
thing. It is entirely American. It is
not um something that is that they have
copied from the British as far as I can
understand. It is all to give the people
the illusion of having a democracy. See,
we are giving you two choices.
Republicans versus Democrats. You choose
what you want. See, it's a democracy.
You get to vote, right? Even though
nothing changes. Um the deep state is
what owns everything. The deep state
owns the United States. They also own
the British crown and whatever else.
Um,
so does deep state behave the same way
as the British? Well, they are an
imperial power. The deep state that the
British crown was an imperial power,
wasn't it? The British Empire, the sun
never set over the British Empire. Well,
today the sun never sets over the
American Empire. The American Empire has
possessions, explicit implicit
possessions all across the world. It has
vasalized more than half the world's
countries, significantly more than half
the world's countries. These are all
American possessions. The sun never sets
there. It occupies various countries
like Japan, like South Korea, like
Germany, like Italy and so on to in
various ways. Japan and South Korea is
very explicit. Germany is slightly less
explicit. Italy even less explicit and
there are other countries as well. So it
behaves in the in the way any empire
behaves and there is no surprise there.
6P70 Delta says, "It is said logistics
win wars. US and former USSR operated
tremendously large transport aircrafts
in large numbers. Is India in bad shape
since most of its fleet is aging and
near the end of its lifetime? Are we
sleeping? We are sleeping.
Whatever transport aircraft, the
tremendously large ones we have are of
foreign origin,
Russian origin, some of those and
American origin. So we need US help and
generosity and benevolence to get the
spare parts and all that for those
American fighter planes the Hercules and
whatn not we have right
um
we have been sleeping we are still
sleeping why aren't we developing our
own transport aircraft why aren't we
doing any of these things
a project doesn't even exist to develop
something in the next 20 years 30 years
We are sleeping. We are not a serious
nation to a very large extent. Yeah.
We need transport aircraft that we
control, that we own, that we don't have
to rely on other nations for spare parts
and so on for, right?
We simply haven't bothered with these
things. Seriously,
you know, not serious.
It's a we are a nation of slogans. Super
power, visha guru. Are we doing what it
takes? No, we're not.
Nobody says what if USA bombed by Russia
then USA will bomb Russia.
Ritik says are north Afghanistan and
Iran pro- India and antipac. What type
of government does Iran have? Does the
president have power or is the true
leader? What type of government does
Iran have? It has a theocratic
government. It has a president and so
on.
and a modulus. But the president doesn't
really have doesn't he's like the fourth
most powerful person or something in the
country. The real power is in the li is
lies in the hands of the supreme leader,
right? The poet.
Yeah, he's a poet. He used to be a poet.
I'm sure he still is a poet at heart.
You can still see some of his poetry on
Twitter.
Okay. Now, so that's what Iran is.
That's the kind of government they have.
They have a theocratic government. Okay.
Um and Afghanistan is a very similar
government. They also have a theocratic
government, an Islamic government. Iran
is Shia. Afghanistan is Sunni. But okay.
Uh and look, they are not anti-PAC. They
just don't want Pakistan there. Pakistan
is a nuisance.
Ideally, both would like to be friends
with Pakistan because Pakistan is is an
Islamic country. But Pakistan is a
nuisance. Pakistan is a terrorist nation
and Pakistan is a puppet of foreign
powers and it's always been used by
foreign powers to destabilize these two
countries. So neither Afghanistan nor
Iran are in any way whatsoever happy
that they have Pakistan as a neighbor.
Both would prefer to have India as a
neighbor as used to be in the past. Um
so because of circumstances because of
the cruelty
of the universe because they have
Pakistan as a neighbor both of them
obviously are antipakistan if someone
keeps on poking you and stabbing you
you're going to be anti them right so
both are because of that antipakistan
and pro- India
James says Europe boasts superior
weather refinement and architecture
India lament mentable state rather
justifies its place in the so-called
third world or dare say well it depends
on what your what your idea of superior
weather is some people like warm weather
I mean most Americans want to retire in
Florida which is a place with warm
weather and humid weather it's kind of
like Bombay or Chennai Mumbai or Chennai
right Florida not as warm But I can show
you plenty of places in in India which
have weather that's similar to Miami.
Miami for example. So why do Americans
not consider the weather of New York or
Boston
or Maryland
or or Salt Lake City to be nice? Why do
they want to migrate to Miami or
Florida? Why is that? Yeah. So it
depends. I'm not sure. So superior
weather for one person will be terrible
weather for another person.
Um so Europe boast superior weather.
Well I have I've been to Europe. Some of
the weather is terrible. Go to England.
The weather is ghastly. Ghastly. Four
seasons in one day. What's that?
Rains. It's gloomy. Terrible. You call
that superior. Come on. What you
smoking, bro?
Um and refine. What's refinement? You
you eat rice with a fork. You put it on
the back of the fork and then you eat it
thus thusly. You call that refinement. I
call that idiosi.
Architecture.
We got superior architecture. Okay.
Today's Indian architecture post 1947
Indian architecture is is lamentable
question. No question about that. But
our civilizational architecture is
superior to yours.
um lamentable state rather justifies it
place in see right now India deservedly
is a third world country no question but
we're going to rise again we're going to
have better leaders in the future okay
no one can keep us down our historical
position was always at the top and we're
going to get back there whenever it
happens I dare say always great to talk
to you Mr. James always great to have
your
questions and comments. Roshi Vharma
says, "What's your biggest praise and
criticism of criticism of India on the
global stage given the current state of
geopolitics?"
My biggest praise and biggest criticism
of India, biggest praise is that we are
standing up on to the bullies.
We are not giving up our sovereignty. It
is commendable. It's very high risk.
It's especially high risk for the
leader, the prime minister. He's taking
a personal risk.
That is commendable,
right? It's so easy to to cave in and to
to buckle to to the superpowers's
demands. It's so easy to do that. But
the prime minister has chosen not to do
that do that. He has chosen to take the
difficult decision of keeping India
sovereign and not caving into American
de maximalist demands. I cannot praise
that enough.
I have the highest praise for that.
Highest praise. What's my criticism of
India on the global stage
criticism? Biggest criticism of India on
the global stage. Well, overall our
diplomacy is good. Our the way we one of
the criticisms I would give is that we
don't engage enough with the third world
with the global south. Okay. We should
have
more more robust more rigorous
engagement with the African nations with
Southeast Asian nations
in a meaningful way. That's one. Um
apart from that, India is not taking the
actions that we need to take to make
India more powerful in the future
internally,
which is the the hard decisions, the
hard reforms. We're not doing that. Ease
of doing business, nothing changes.
taxation system extremely
over complicated,
right? Um the alleged corruption, all of
these things matter geopolitically also.
The alleged corruption, the the the the
rotten system, various rotten
institutions, the horrific education
system which will perpetually keep India
mediocre. So that's my biggest
criticism. None of these are difficult
things, but the current government
doesn't seem to have the gumption to
take on these issues. And another big
criticism, huge criticism of mine is
this. Well, too, why don't we have a
more powerful navy? We have the
position that that is gifted by the
gods, a ge geographic position. We
dominate the Indian Ocean region, but
our navy, it's like a glorified coast
guard most of it. We should have at
least 50 submarines.
We should have distributed lethality
lethality with with at least 300.
vessels that are capable of carrying
missiles.
None of this is being done, right?
That's my that's one of the the big
criticisms.
And what else do I have?
I'm sure there was something on my mind,
but it seems to have slipped out, right?
Um what other criticism do I have?
I'm sure something or other will come up
later on.
um
army, air force, all of that needs to be
taken care of and so on. Yeah. Okay. AVM
says most of internet data is from the
west. How can India achieve
technological sovereignty after building
its own own LLM since it doesn't have
quality training data? For that first of
all we need to have Indian social media
platforms
which will generate Indian data not
western data. You see it's all step by
step. You have to build one thing on top
of another. Why do the Chinese have
their own data? Because they have their
own social media platforms. Huge
highquality social media platforms.
Their whole entire population is on
that. We don't have that.
Uh secondly, our education institutions
produce very mediocre research. If you
train your LLMs on that, your LLMs will
have an IQ of 82,
right? That's another issue.
And uh what else? We we can train our
LLMs on our own literature which is
enormous. We have an enormous classical
literature. We can train that the LMS on
that. So you know we will have to
resolve these issues by building our own
platforms network things and all that
but we we want to take shortcuts
then what's the point of doing anything
at all if you want to take all the
shortcuts
right
yeah technological sovereignty very
important uh poll says do you think that
historical historic events like
Bolshevik revolution or Chinese or
Russian revolution or holocaust affect
current geopolitics or one country's
agenda or future goals are always based
on current interests. No, these historic
events do affect current geopolitics.
Absolutely they do. The the Bolevik
revolution left behind a big legacy
which which gave rise to the USSR and
the dissolution of the USSR gave rise to
to present day Russia and some of the
territories Russia lost as a consequence
of the break up of the USSR are Russian
territories and maybe Russia wants them
back and maybe Russia you know so the
Bolevik revolution does affect current
geopolitics.
Um the Holocaust very much plays a role
even today in current geopolitics right
what you can say what you can't say what
nations are considered good what nations
are considered to be permanently evil uh
the nations that were on the losing side
in the second world war are permanently
considered to be evil and are under
under permanent geopolitical under
permanent military occupation by the
winning power which was which was the US
right so today's geopolitics is indeed
affected by by past events
And whatever see for for example
the second world war was a direct
consequence of World War I. Germany was
humiliated badly at the end of World War
I which is what gave rise to World War
II. So past history was the causitative
factor of a future war. Right? So
everything is based on past, present,
future. All everything intertwines.
So a country's agenda and and goals,
they are based on current interests as
well as historical events and
aspirations that that are tied to
historical events.
Maharvs says, "Do you support a CCP
style single party rule in India? I
think CCP's state controlled
marketdriven economy worked very well in
India. Why isn't India adopting such a
system? It would improve our economy."
See why isn't India adopting such a
system? Because the entire structure of
the system is such that it will not
allow this to happen.
We have this weak federal system in the
country where the states have a lot of
power of their own and the central
government can't interfere there in
various things which are state matters,
state affairs,
right? Law and order is a state subject.
That's what you will hear a lot of the
time. Which means the central government
can't do a thing about the law and order
situation in a state and until until it
goes so bad that you have to impose
president's rule and even if you impose
president's rule in a state they can go
to the Supreme Court and have it
overturned.
So you see the system is such that it is
designed to keep India weak and
decentralized.
If someone tries to implement a CCB sty
style system in India, a central command
structure, all the states will rise up
in protest. They won't they won't allow
this to happen. You will need a very
powerful leader to impose this on the
country.
Do I support such a such a party rule in
India? Single party rule. I do. As long
as the single party is is pro- India and
and not evil, benevolent to the people
and to the country and is is capable
essentially we talking about a
benevolent dictatorship
which essentially means a monarchy or
imperial rule like we had in the past so
many times. That's exactly what it is.
CCP style single party rule is an
imperial system. The old Chinese
imperial system that's what it is. So
the Indian equivalent of that would be
going back to the times of Chandra Gupta
Moria or Ashok or Kaneshka or the
various Gupta emperors or the Cholas or
the Marata Empire. That's what it means.
Do I support that? It will it will be
way more beneficial to India than than
the the system that we have today. Yeah.
But it won't be allowed to happen. Why
will not will it not be allowed to
happen? Because all the politicians in
India who are in whatever positions of
power, they have come to these positions
of power through the current system. Why
will they change the system that brought
them to power? They will oppose any
attempt to change it for their own
personal interests,
not the nation's interest.
Ashoto says does what does the US deep
state gain from ongoing and future
conflicts like Israel, Iran,
UA, Ukraine, Russia, Afghanistan,
Pakistan, China, Taiwan by creating
chaos across the world, you gain more
control
and by when two nations are fighting,
Afghanistan, Pakistan, if your guy is
Pakistan, you want Pakistan to win.
then you have more
uh power position capabilities. If
Pakistan can defeat Afghanistan and take
over Afghanistan, then the US can get 20
air bases in Afghanistan if they want.
So that is benefit for the US for the
deep state. Uh Israel Iran if Israel
defeats Iran and does a regime in Iran
then the Americans once again can take
over Thran and Iran and take all the oil
from Iran. Is it not great? Huge
benefit. China, Taiwan. Well, as long as
China is not able to invade Taiwan and
occupy Taiwan, it's a win for the US
because Taiwan cuts, you know, it's part
of the first island chain that cuts,
which is a huge problem for the Chinese
navy.
And it's always this this thing that
stares China in the face that, you know,
you're so weak, so powerless that you
can't take an island that that's in your
backyard and it it allows the US to
project power across various parts of
China from Taiwan. These are all big
benefits, right?
Shria Spitra says, "Thank you for all
the knowledge. I learned a lot by
watching your shows. Thank you. I wish I
had teachers like you in in school. I
wish I had better teachers in school."
Seriously. Anyway, thank you so much. I
really appreciate it. Yeah, this is I
mean, you know, knowledge has to be made
interesting. It can't be this boring,
dull, droning BS that you get in in
textbooks. It has to make sense. You
have to understand causality, cause and
effect. All of that has to be explained.
Otherwise, knowledge is not knowledge.
It's it's just boredom. So anyway, thank
you so much. I really appreciate that.
Thank you, sir. Uh 6P70 Delta said, "I
meant you open maps very rarely
nowadays." Okay. Well, I just did that
for your question, right? Okay. Okay.
Got it. Got it. AJ Sharma says,
"Question two. US doesn't care yet
spreads its culture as Europe declines.
Could the US deep state driven by old EU
history be behind this revenge?"
Which revenge? You mean declined?
A US deep state driven by old European
history.
US doesn't care yet spreads its culture
as US Europe declines. What is American
culture?
American culture used to be the old
European culture anyway. But yeah,
they've developed their own. Okay. Do
you mean that LGBTQ thing and all that
which they are spreading these days?
Yeah, that is American culture. Uh
degeneracy
um and uh whatever LG I'm not saying
LGBTQ is degeneracy. I'm saying
everything else is degeneracy
and also LGBTQ.
So US culture is degeneracy on one hand
and another thing is LGBTQ and the other
thing is freedom, human rights, all that
all those slogans which are hollow
slogans. Uh so is America spreading its
culture? I'm not sure it's spreading its
culture. It's probably spreading
propaganda through Hollywood and what
not. Now the the question is um could
the US deep state driven by old European
history be behind this revenge? I'm not
sure what you're asking sir. What are
you asking?
Which revenge? That Europe is declining.
Of course the US deep state is behind
that. The US is behind that. Why is
Europe declining? it its decline is
being engineered
using Brussels
as the as the tool of engineering and
Brussels is controlled entirely by the
US from Washington.
So the decline of Europe is being
engineered by the United States. Of
course it is. Is it revenge? I don't
think it's about revenge of any kind.
It's nothing to do with revenge. It's
about creating the right kind of world
that you envision for yourself. And in
this world view Europe it it should not
matter a lot.
Um so it's not
any form of revenge or whatever. It's
just that they are shaping reshaping the
world the kind of they they're trying to
create a different kind of world for
themselves and this has nothing to do
with old EU history.
Ryik says imagine we take Gilgat
Baltistan someday maybe after 30 40
years. Then what will happen to the
locals of P? I know they don't like
India but they are radical.
That's an open question.
That's an open question. What will
happen?
We will eventually take back these
territories. But what about the people?
The people who are there currently local
there. They don't like India. They have
no love for India. They don't uh they
have no love for Indian culture which
used to be the culture of their
ancestors. But they don't have any love
for that. They have significant hatred
for that. What do we do about them? I
think that's a question that uh is an
open question. I don't have an answer to
the question. Okay.
6P70 Delta says why US universities are
great but schools are mostly crap. Most
American universities are also becoming
crap today.
I mean if you have crap schools, they're
going to send crap students to the US
universities. And the kind of professors
you have in US universities, especially
in the humanities,
they further mess up students minds. So
even US universities aren't that great
anymore today. By the way, it's only the
few Ivy League universities that still
have some some kind of standards.
Um but when it comes to the STEM
subjects, science and technology
subjects, they still have high
standards, right? So if you are studying
in a US university even not in the top
100 in the US maybe let's say it's
ranked 120 in the US even then you will
get a far better science education than
you will get in India right so they have
maintained the the standards in science
and technology but in other subjects ah
they are full of propaganda and and
ideology right So it is what it is. So
this this great takeover of the US
educational system, it started in the
1950s and60s when the leftists started
slowly, gradually, quietly, silently
taking over everything and now it's
become very open. So that's mainly in
the fields of the humanities and so on
and on US campuses you can't express
certain opinions and so on. That's
become the norm everywhere essentially.
So that is the situation right now. Mr.
Senna says when did the deep state's
influence truly begin?
I would say after the end of the second
world war
um
after the Bretonwoods agreement 1944
when the US uh um dollar became the was
was accepted as the world's global
reserve currency. So around that time
the deep state's influence becomes very
powerful. Did the deep state exist
before that? probably it did but it was
not globally powerful until that time.
So maybe it existed maybe the deep state
had its genesis in the beginning of the
20th century. Maybe before that
but once again what is the deep state?
We don't quite know. Who are the people
who make up the deep state? We don't
quite know. They own the Federal
Reserve. So maybe when the Federal
Reserve formed that's when the deep
state's influence begins. So there are
different ways of looking at it. But uh
if you want a clear date it's around
1944 1945 and eventually they become so
powerful that even a US president
president is bombed off 1963.
Uh Harab says please listen to Mary Maka
Mary Maka by thievery corporation. Okay
I don't know what that is but I'll check
it out. Thank you. James says a single
shelf of a good European library was
worth the whole native literature of
India and Arabia. Lord Macaulay. Well,
you are indeed correctly quoting Lord
Macaulay. Lord Macaulay
expressed this opinion. He made this
assertion. A single shelf of a good
European library is worth more than the
entire native literature of India and
Arabia. I'm not sure why he put India
and Arabia together because there's no
comparison. And today most Indians
believe this. So I would uh you know I
would congratulate you James that your
Lord Mau has been indeed so successful
that today many Indians believe this to
be true. Yeah. Yeah. It is what it is
what it is. This has been successful
this propaganda. Ritik says the US has
surrounded India by regime changes all
around.
Why can't they change regime in their
enemies like Iran, North Korea? Can the
US regime change Kim Jong-un and Ayat?
Can the US make North Korea public?
Break statues of Kimlong.
See the US can do this in different
ways. Whenever you have so-called
democratic systems, they can affect they
can do a regime change by the color
revolution
methodology.
Hm.
So you take the help of the local army,
you pay them whatever they want and then
you create a fake student revolution and
then at the last moment the army takes
over and they said that the students
have won
and then yeah so that's one way of doing
it. That can only be done where you have
a impoverished third world nation with
no self-respect and and a corrupt nation
where the army is available for
purchase. Right? That's what you can do
there. and various politicians are will
can easily come into your pockets. So
that's the situation in this
subcontinent in every country in the
subcontinent not not the not in India in
India the army is not for sale that that
we can tell for sure other elements
politicians of various parties
potentially for sale possibly
hypothetically allegedly potentially
some maybe perhaps okay and NOS's are a
great means of doing it so wherever you
have democratic systems or quasi
democratic fake you know somewhat
democratic systems you can use the color
revolution methodology.
So Bangladesh is very much like
Pakistan. That's why they were able to
do a regime change like they did in
Pakistan in 2022. Similarly, they did
something in Bangladesh in 2024, which
is something I had predicted in a video
9 months before that. In Nepal, once
again, they've done something similar.
So Nepal again was kind of a democracy,
right? That's why they were able to do
this. Uh they would like to do that in
India as well. Now Iran is not a
democracy. They have elections and stuff
but you know the president of Iran is
just the fourth most most powerful
person in the country. So it's not
really a democracy. North Korea is a
clear dictatorship there. The US can't
do that because you can't have NOS's
there. Won't be allowed. You can't buy
politicians there. Those politicians
will be hanged or shot. So they can't do
these things there. You see the benefits
of not having a democracy. You won't
have people available for sale. And in
these countries Iran and North Korea,
the army is not for sale once again. So
the way the US can change regime there
is by launching an actual invasion.
Yeah, that's how it goes. So different
kinds of nations, different tactics and
strategies.
Chat DSP says, I sometimes wish I had
not found you.
Uh with so much happening in your
teachings that develop my critical
thinking, I now see reality and it's
scary. Awaiting next books in volumes of
you. Thank you so much. Thank you so
much. I really appreciate what you're
saying. I really appreciate that.
You know one sometimes wishes that you
you know you sometimes wish that you do
not know what you know.
You sometimes you know feel nostalgic
about the time when you were a child
when you were like 9 10 years old when
you thought you understood the world and
you thought the world was so beautiful
and so pretty flowers and butterflies
and stuff. Eventually when you grow up
in when you actually grow up when you
realize what the world is really like uh
would I change things would I want to go
back to the time when I was 9 years old
and understood nothing about the world
probably not it was beautiful time of
life of course but it's always good to
know what's happening I know it's scary
it's so dirty
you know but it's the way the world has
always been the world has always been
like this nasty cutthroat backststepping
you know, dirty politics, all of that.
It's always been like that. It's been
like that 5,000 years ago also. There's
always been e forces of evil, forces of
good, forces that are gray, shades of
gray. It's always been like this. So,
yeah, you know, once you realize the way
things are, you know, you kind of feel
like you've lost your own innocence and
you wish you had not learned these
things. It is what it is, you know. Uh
yeah, next books volumes coming out will
keep coming out. All right. Thank you so
much, sir. Thank you. Ankit GI says,
"Thank you so much for your time and
effort. Really inspiring." Thank you so
much, ma'am. I really appreciate the
support of everybody including you,
ma'am. I really appreciate that. Thank
you very much.
Ankur Saraf, thank you so much sir.
Really appreciate that.
Uh Gagenbut says the US just slapped
100% tariffs on China yet he is under
immense pressure to set ties right with
India. What leverage does India have
against the US that Trump could not do
much to India though Modi hurt his ego?
India has no leverage in the US. What
leverage does India have? Not much. Not
much.
Um the US slapped tariffs on China
because the Chinese have impo imposed
massive export restrictions on various
rare earth elements magnets and so on
which are critical to the US defense
let's say war industry now they call it
war right no longer defense they're
these elements are critical to the US
military and the manufacturing of US
weapons and stuff so the Chinese are
have imposed export restrictions on
those and that's why the Americans have
retaliated by imposing these 100%
tariffs on China. But you know they
can't do a thing about the Chinese
export restrictions. So China has
massive leverage over the US. What
leverage does who is under immense
pressure to set ties right with India?
Trump is not under any immense pressure.
I'm not sure how you have understood
that he is under immense pressure to set
ties right with India. I would say that
Trump is under no pressure to set ties
right with India. He's in no hurry to do
that. India has as far as I can see not
a lot of leverage. We have some
leverage. We supply 40% of uh of the um
you know the generic medicines that the
US has and our our cyber coolies are the
backbone of the US tech tech fortune 500
companies and all that but that's
limited leverage.
So I don't think India has a tremendous
amount of leverage over the US and Trump
has indeed done a lot to hurt India
hasn't he? I mean the the 50% tariffs on
India is is already a lot. Secondly
Trump openly siding with Pakistan. Isn't
that a massive massive blow to India?
So
yeah Trump is doing a lot to hurt India.
SK is a new member. Thank you so much
sir and welcome so much s ma'am. Thank
you so much and welcome. Ankur Saraf is
also a new member. Thank you so much. I
really appreciate I really appreciate
that. Thank you so much. Rahul says, I
read world system analysis by Emmanuel
Walterin recently. It's very legit
despite it being Marxist. Could you
please give in-depth analysis
for that to happen? I will have to study
it myself. I still haven't done that.
So, okay. I appreciate the book
recommendation first of all and the
suggestion to do to give an in-depth
analysis. So I'll put this in my list of
books that I should read sometime in the
future and uh once I do that I will
definitely give an in-depth analysis but
it's not possible right now because I
haven't read it sir. Okay. Um
6P70 Delta says your opinion on a IM can
you have another podcast with him? Yeah,
I am Habitatra. Super sharp guy. I
really like the guy. Great guy. Good
friends of good friend of mine. Um yeah,
I would love to do another podcast with
him whenever the opportunity arises for
sure. Yeah, I I don't necessarily agree
with everything he says but extremely
sharp person and definitely pro India.
India definitely not international. So
what else can you ask for? Can you can
you expect you you to agree? Can you
expect to agree with everything someone
says? Not necessarily.
But I would love to do another podcast
with him whenever the opportunity
arises.
Shashi Dhankar says there's some chatter
about Trump's health. Do you see him
stepping back or being replaced? Would a
replacement be better for India in any
way? Okay, there's been some chatter
about Trump's health. Trump is obviously
like around 80ish, right? What's his
age? Let's quickly find out. Let's
quickly Google it. Yes. Trump
age 79 years. He's 79 years old, which
is like 80ish, like I said, that's a
pretty advanced age. He's pretty elderly
by by any standards. And at that age,
even if you have a good lifestyle,
you're going to have some health issues
or the other. So, there's been all kinds
of chatter. You know, there are there is
this makeup that is applied to his to
his to the back of his hand. At times,
sometimes he looks very tired. So
sometimes he looks like he's got swollen
ankles or something. So there are there
is all this chatter about his health. Do
I see him stepping back or being
replaced? Well, if his health does
deteriorate, it doesn't look like it's
it's bad right now. From whatever I've
seen of him in the latest, you know,
appearances in the in public, he look he
looks fine. Uh he's still playing golf
and stuff. you know, he did some kind of
a video with his granddaughter Kai uh in
which he's driving the golf cart and the
girl, his granddaughter is interviewing
him. So, he looks pretty okay there. But
you never know some health issue may
crop up in the future. Uh one hopes for
the people of the US and for the nation
that doesn't happen. But if it does
happen as can happen, then it's possible
that he may have to step back depending
on the nature of the health crisis. So
if that happens then there's a clear
line of success succession if the
president is no longer able to carry out
his duties then the vice president takes
over as the president it happens. So it
could happen potentially possibly in
sometime in the future or it may not
happen. Would a replacement be better
for India in any way? No will make no
difference.
None whatsoever. Shashi G.
Okay. Okay. Shiva Rajput says 2.5 front
war in Pakistan after accepting Israel a
nation.
So has Pakistan recognized Israel?
Not sure.
2.5 front war in Pakistan. Um see right
now there's a 1.5 or one front war. Half
front is Afghanistan border which is not
exactly a war right now but it's
skirmishes and and military action. And
the other 0.5 front is the terrorists
within Pakistan. Some are controlled by
the Pakistani government. Some are
controlled by the Pakistani military.
Some are anti-Pakistan.
Some are some want freedom like
Balojasthan. Some in Synindel. So so
Pakistan is is a mess. It's always been
a mess
>> and they are trying to test the patience
of the Taliban. So they are also facing
some consequences of that. So that is
the situation right now. I I'm not sure
I would call it uh 2.5 war unless they
get involved with India again in which
case it will be a disaster for Pakistan.
So that's where we are right now. Okay.
Uh Chad DSP says, "My two twin
two-year-old twin boys are innocent,
joyful, playful.
I hope it lasts as long as it is humanly
possible. The nicest be most beautiful
time for children who have good parents
is the early years of life when every
the world is so beautiful where you're
super innocent you don't know anything
about the nastiness of the world and you
get to play and you have no pressures no
burdens yeah take care of your kids and
I wish them all the best sir or ma'am
thank you uh AJ Sharma says question
three more specific one group suffers
the most in European history. Now they
are taking revenge in the form of deep
state from EU just observation. Are you
referring to our friends the Jews? The
Jews have been persecuted tremendously
in European history. No question about
that. But I would not really agree.
Okay, let me explain. I would not really
agree that the Jews have been the one
group that have suffered the most in
European history.
The truth is that the group that has
suffered the most in European history
are the Romani people.
They have suffered far worse than the
Jews and their plight is deliberately
suppressed and hidden. They still suffer
from all kinds of prejudice in Europe.
They are still regarded as secondass
citizens in many countries in Europe.
They are still stateless in many parts
of Europe. And the Nazis persecuted them
horribly
despite the Romani people being of the
actual Arian ancestry, not the Germans.
The Germans are fake Arians. The only
Arian people are the people of the
subcontinent and Persia. So India,
Indian subcontinent including
Afghanistan and Persia. These are the
real Arians and the gypsies or the
Romanian people are the original Arians
because they are descendants of Indians
and yet they were persecuted by the
Germans, the Nazis.
I would say the the Gummani have
suffered way more than the Jews. Um but
are are you implying that Jews are
taking revenge on on Europe in form of
the deep state? Well if you say so okay
sir
observation. All right sir
says a podcast with Sep Balak Krishna
and Omen on dark ages of India. I would
love to do that in the future. See right
now I'm not really doing podcasts. The
thing about podcast is that now
everybody has a podcast. Podcasting has
become a cottage industry.
Podcasts are like noise today. Everybody
is doing dark history of this and dark
truth of that and
you know secrets of this and secrets of
that. My goodness, I'm so sick of this
this Indian podcasting industry.
It provides no value whatsoever anymore
to anybody.
So right now I'm I've stepped back from
doing podcasts. It doesn't it doesn't
mean that I'll not do podcast again but
only with selected guests that interest
me. So I certainly I've done with
Sepalak Krishna in the past is a good
good friend of mine. I'd love to do with
him again and I can certainly look into
Mr. Omandrau what he does. Uh I do know
him. I have met him in Jaipur multiple
times but um certainly can consider that
as well. No question about it. So thank
you for the recommendations. Thank you.
Duresh says, "What is the worst case
scenario if India doesn't develop in 25
years considering how bad our cities
are? I don't think it will. Things can
change. Things certainly can change. One
one should remain optimistic. The cities
are terribly bad, right? It's not like
they've gone backwards since 1914. No,
they've not become worse since 1914.
probably they have become slightly
betterish since 2014 but they're still
horrible India cities
look
Kabul has better roads than most Indian
cities allegedly h
countries with less GDP per capita than
India do far better than India clearly
there is something rotten within the
Indian system and if that is not fixed
India will never develop what's the
worst case scenario India never develops
India becomes then eventually you will
have a government that will vasalize
India and then you will have another 250
years of East India Company rule or the
equivalent of that through some other
country. So if India doesn't fix these
issues sooner or later you will have a
government that will vasalize India.
This government won't do it but they're
not fixing the issues the the core
issues the alleged corruption and the
the deep systemic reforms that are
desperately needed in India.
So eventually people will at some point
in time vote for a different government
whoever that may be. Okay, I'm not
saying it'll be X or Y or Zed. I'm
saying whoever that may be. There's a
possibility that this other government
that may come in, whoever it is may
happily vasalize India. Then we are
enslaved for another 250 years, maybe a
thousand years. That's the worst case
scenario. And it's a it's a scenario
with a not non negligible probability
considering the lack of
lack of reforms in India.
Okay. Rahul says world system funnels
wealth from periphery to core. Okay sir.
Okay. There's no question here but okay
sir. Thank you so much for this
observation.
Rushi Jooshi says namaste. Namaste G.
when we speak about the deep state the
US and how they have continued
throughout the centuries should India
have this in the future so the US deep
state has it continued through the
centuries I'm not sure it's continued
through the centuries uh it probably
originates sometime in the late 19th
century or early 20th century around
that time and they have remained hidden
and they have created this this facade
of democracy
which is enough to fool people and
that's how they rule the US and through
the US they rule the world Okay. Uh,
should India have this in the have this
in the future? Well, depends. If it is a
deep state that is non- evil, if it's a
Dharmic deep state, I would be very much
in favor of that. But if it's an evil
deep state, well, then we might as well
as well accept the US deep state in that
case. Did I just say they are evil? Oh
my goodness. Oh my goodness. What did I
say? Right. So, that's the deal. Uh,
Vamshi Khim says, "You are near 300
episodes. Do a 6 to 8 hour episode.
I did one 8 hour episode, which ended up
being an almost 9 hour episode. Would
you like me to do that? Would you like
me to make the 300th episode an 8 hour
episode again? Let me know. Let me know
if you want me to do an 8 hour episode
in
for the 300th episode. If if if that's
what everyone wants, I'll be happy to do
it. I had no idea that I was I was
capable of doing that. But I spoke for
nearly 9 hours in that episode. At the
end of the episode, I was wondering
whether I'll be able to speak the next
day, whether my throat will be ruined.
But it turned out to be okay. I spoke
very little the next day. It turned out
to be okay. So I I guess I have the
vocal codes that can last 8 n hours. So
if you all want I can do an 8 hour
episode uh on number 300.
Uh Rahul Lakman says how about Ankit
Sha's PC guest. Well thank you for the
recommendation sir. Thank you.
All right. Uh this brings us to the end
of today's episode. No more super chats.
So I will end it here. Two and a half
hours gone. It was supposed to be 2our
episode. Uh so
uh one second. injured soccer player
says, "Thank you for enlighting us. Do
you foresee a Kalistthani nation forming
from within Canada?" I would love that
to happen. If the Kalistthanis want a
nation, I I would urge them to to create
a nation in in Canada, a Kalistthan in
Canada. Um, where's the question gone?
Here it is. Yeah, let let them make in
Canada. Do I foresee it happening? I
think it's unlikely to happen.
>> But I would I would support a Kalistan
in Canada if if that's what they want.
Not in India, not anywhere in in the
subcontinent. They can have it in Canada
if they like, but the Canadians have to
give them the land for that. I don't
really see foresee this happening. The
Kalistanis are a bunch of useful idiots
who are being used against their own
people. Sadly,
Shivaraj puts us Hindi GP series for
uneducated people like UPH. What is the
GP series?
Hindi GP series.
Um
what is the GPC? I'm not I'm not really
sure what you're saying sir. Um look if
people speak Hindi it doesn't first of
all look if people speak Hindi it
doesn't mean they are uneducated. There
can be people who are highly literate
who don't speak English. Okay. So
English is not some high language that
makes you superior and makes you more
educated. And I'm not sure what you're
saying GP series. Are you saying I
should do some Hindi Q&As?
I've done that in the past. I'm not that
good. I mean I'm I'm speak Hindi very
well but my Hindi isn't the best even
though I can speak it fluently and I
like I prefer not to use the foreign
loan words
especially on a public platform that's
why I stay away from Hindi mostly anyway
thank you very much sir for your
recommendation
okay I think that brings us to the end
of okay Ankur Saraf is saying Hindi
geopolitics series oh that's what you're
asking Um,
okay. I'll I'll keep that in mind. Right
now, I have no plans for that.
All right. Okay.
Live chat for 300 podcast. We'll look
into that.
Okay. So, thank you so much for all the
questions. I'm going to end this here.
We've crossed two and a half hours. It
was supposed to be two hours, but I
always always enjoy taking the questions
from you all. And let's end this here. I
look forward to seeing you in the live
streams next week. We shall continue
doing this. Please keep learning. Please
keep asking questions, the right
questions to the right people. Keep
raising your standards. Doesn't matter
if the government is not raising the
standards and keeping India mediocre or
whatever, whichever government, state,
center, whatever you would like to talk
about, but you can raise your own
individual standards. All right? Please
do that. Take care. Thank you. See you
next week. Bye-bye.